There is no audience here tonight in this hall at the National Constitution Center.
今晚在这个大厅里没有观众，这里是美国宪法中心。
This is an intimate setting for two candidates who have never met.
这是一个亲密的场合，两位从未见过的候选人将在此相遇。
President Trump won the coin toss.
特朗普总统赢得了掷硬币的胜利。
He chose to deliver the final closing statement of the evening.
他选择了在今晚的辩论中发表最后的闭幕词。
Vice President Harris selected the podium to the right.
哈里斯副总统选择了右边的讲台。
So let's now welcome the candidates to the stage.
现在让我们欢迎两位候选人上台。
Vice President Kamala Harris and President Donald Trump.
哈里斯副总统和特朗普总统。
Kamala Harris, let's have a good debate.
卡马拉·哈里斯，让我们进行一场精彩的辩论。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Welcome to you both.
欢迎你们两位。
It's wonderful to have you.
很高兴见到你们。
It's an honor to have you both here tonight.
今晚能邀请到你们两位，真是荣幸。
Good evening.
晚上好。
We are looking forward to a spirited and thoughtful debate.
我们期待一场充满活力和深思熟虑的辩论。
So let's get started.
那么，让我们开始吧。
I want to begin tonight with the issue that voters repeatedly say is their number one issue, and that is the economy and the cost of living in this country.
今晚我想从选民反复提到的首要问题开始，那就是经济和这个国家的日常生活成本。
Vice President Harris, you and President Trump were elected four years ago, and your opponent on the stage here tonight often asks his supporters, are you better off than you were four years ago?
哈里斯副总统，你和特朗普总统四年前当选，而今晚你的对手在台上经常问他的支持者，你们比四年前过得更好吗？
When it comes to the economy, do you believe Americans are better off than they were four years ago?
在经济方面，你认为美国人民比四年前过得更好吗？
So, I was raised as a middle class kid, and I am actually the only person on this stage who has a plan that is about lifting up the middle class and working people of America.
我是在中产阶级家庭长大的，实际上我是唯一一个在这个舞台上提出提升中产阶级和工人阶级计划的。
I believe in the ambition, the aspirations, the dreams of the American people.
我相信美国人民的雄心、抱负和梦想。
And that is why I imagine and have actually a plan to build what I call an opportunity economy.
这就是为什么我想象并实际上有一个计划来建立我称之为机会经济的计划。
Because here's the thing.
因为事实是。
We know that we have a shortage of homes and housing.
我们知道我们住房短缺。
And the cost of housing is too expensive for far too many people.
而且对太多人来说，住房成本太高了。
We know that young families need support.
我们知道年轻家庭需要支持。
to raise their children, and I intend on extending a tax cut for those families of $6,000, which is the largest child tax credit that we have given in a long time, so that those young families can afford to buy a crib, buy a car seat, buy clothes for their children.
来抚养他们的孩子，我打算为这些家庭延长6000美元的税收减免，这是我们很长时间以来给予的最大儿童税收抵免，这样年轻家庭就能负担得起购买婴儿床、汽车座椅和孩子的衣服。
My passion, one of them, is small businesses.
我的热情之一，就是小企业。
I was actually – my mother raised my sister and me, but there was a woman who helped raise us.
实际上，我的母亲抚养了我和我的妹妹，但有一位女士帮助抚养了我们。
We call her our second mother.
我们称她为我们的第二位母亲。
She was a small business owner.
她是一位小企业主。
I love our small businesses.
我喜欢我们的小企业。
My plan is to give a $50,000 tax deduction to startup small businesses, knowing they are part of the backbone of America's economy.
我的计划是给初创小企业提供5万美元的税收减免，因为我知道它们是美国经济的支柱。
My opponent, on the other hand, his plan is to do what he has done before.
而我的对手，他的计划是重复他以前的做法。
which is to provide a tax cut for billionaires and big corporations, which will result in $5 trillion to America's deficit.
也就是为亿万富翁和大公司提供减税，这将导致美国赤字增加5万亿美元。
My opponent has a plan that I call the Trump sales tax, which would be a 20% tax on everyday goods that you rely on to get through the month.
我的对手有一个计划，我称之为特朗普销售税，这将是对你每月依赖的日常商品征收20%的税。
Economists have said that that Trump sales tax would actually result for middle-class families in about $4,000 more a year because of his policies and his ideas about what should be the backs of middle-class people paying for tax cuts for billionaires.
经济学家表示，由于他的政策和关于中产阶级应该为亿万富翁减税买单的想法，特朗普销售税实际上会让中产阶级家庭每年多支出约4000美元。
President Trump.
特朗普总统。
Tariff will be substantial in some cases.
关税在某些情况下会很高。
I took in billions and billions of dollars as you know from China In fact, they never took the tariff off because it was so much money They can't it would totally destroy everything that they've set out to do They're taking in billions of dollars from China and other places They've left the tariffs on when I had it I had tariffs and yet I had no inflation look, we've had a
你知道，我从中国赚了数十亿美元。事实上，他们从未取消关税，因为钱太多了。他们不能取消，那会彻底摧毁他们所做的一切。他们从中国和其他地方赚了数十亿美元。当我执政时，我征收了关税，但我没有通胀。看，我们的经济很糟糕，因为通胀，这实际上是一个国家破坏者。
Terrible economy because inflation has which is really known as a country buster.
它分裂了国家。我们的通胀率是前所未有的，可能是我们国家历史上最严重的。我们曾达到21%，但这还算客气，因为许多东西的价格比几年前高出50%、60%、70%甚至80%。
It breaks up countries We have inflation like very few people have ever seen before probably the worst in our nation's history We were at 21 percent But that's being generous because many things are 50 60 70 and 80 percent higher than they were just a few years ago This has been a disaster for people for the middle class but for every class on top of that we have millions of people pouring into our country from
这对中产阶级和所有阶层的人来说都是一场灾难，而且我们还有数百万人从监狱、精神病院和疯人院涌入我们的国家。
prisons and jails from mental institutions and insane asylums.
他们正在抢走非洲裔美国人、西班牙裔人和工会成员的工作。
And they're coming in and they're taking jobs that are occupied right now by African Americans and Hispanics and also unions.
工会很快就会受到影响。
Unions are going to be affected very soon.
你看到了正在发生的事情。
And you see what's happening.
你看到了美国各地城镇正在发生的事情。
You see what's happening with towns throughout the United States.
你看看俄亥俄州的斯普林菲尔德。
You look at Springfield, Ohio.
你看看科罗拉多州的奥罗拉。
You look at Aurora in Colorado.
他们正在接管这些城镇。
They are taking over the towns.
他们正在占领建筑物。
They're taking over buildings.
他们正在暴力入侵。
They're going in violently.
这些人就是她和拜登放进我们国家的，他们在摧毁我们的国家。
These are the people that she and Biden let into our country, and they're destroying our country.
他们很危险。
They're dangerous.
他们是犯罪率最高的人，我们必须把他们赶出去。
They're at the highest level of criminality, and we have to get them out.
我们必须尽快把他们赶出去。
We have to get them out fast.
我创造了我们国家历史上最伟大的经济之一。
I created one of the greatest economies in the history of our country.
我会再次做到，甚至更好。
I'll do it again and even better.
我们将在这次辩论中讨论移民和边境安全，但我希望让副总统哈里斯在这里回应一下经济问题。
We are going to get to immigration and border security during this debate, but I would like to let Vice President Harris respond on the economy here.
我很乐意。
Well, I would love to.
让我们谈谈唐纳德·特朗普留给我们的是什么。
Let's talk about what Donald Trump left us.
Donald Trump left us the worst unemployment since the Great Depression.
唐纳德·特朗普给我们留下了自大萧条以来最严重的失业问题。
Donald Trump left us the worst public health epidemic in a century.
唐纳德·特朗普带来了一个世纪以来最严重的公共卫生危机。
Donald Trump left us the worst attack on our democracy since the Civil War.
唐纳德·特朗普带来了自内战以来对民主最严重的攻击。
And what we have done is clean up Donald Trump's mess.
而我们所做的，就是清理唐纳德·特朗普留下的烂摊子。
What we have done and what I intend to do is build on what we know are the aspirations and the hopes of the American people.
我们所做的，以及我打算做的，是基于我们所知的美国人民的愿望和希望。
But I'm going to tell you on this debate tonight, you're going to hear from the same old tired playbook.
但我要告诉你们，今晚的辩论中，你们会听到那些老掉牙的陈词滥调。
A bunch of lies, grievances, and name-calling.
一堆谎言、抱怨和人身攻击。
What you're going to hear tonight is a detailed and dangerous plan called Project 2025 that the former president intends on implementing if he were elected again.
今晚你们将听到一个名为“2025计划”的详细而危险的计划，如果前总统再次当选，他打算实施这个计划。
I believe very strongly that the American people want a president who understands the importance of bringing us together, knowing we have so much more in common than what separates us.
我坚信，美国人民需要一位理解团结重要性的总统，知道我们共同点远多于分歧。
And I pledge to you to be a president for all Americans.
我向你们承诺，我会成为所有美国人的总统。
President Trump will give you a minute here to respond.
特朗普总统，给你一分钟时间回应。
Number one, I have nothing to do, as you know, and as she knows better than anyone, I have nothing to do with Project 2025.
首先，我与“2025计划”无关，你知道，她也知道，我与这个计划毫无关系。
That's out there.
那东西在外面。
I haven't read it.
我没读过。
I don't want to read it purposely.
我故意不想读。
I'm not going to read it.
我不会去读它。
This was a group of people that got together.
这是一群人聚在一起。
They came up with some ideas, I guess some good, some bad, but it makes no difference.
他们提出了一些想法，有些好，有些坏，但无所谓。
I have nothing to do.
我与此无关。
Everybody knows I'm an open book.
大家都知道我是个透明的人。
Everybody knows what I'm going to do.
大家都知道我会做什么。
Cut taxes very substantially and create a great economy like I did before.
大幅减税，创造一个像我之前那样伟大的经济。
We had the greatest economy.
我们曾经拥有最伟大的经济。
We got hit with a pandemic.
我们遭遇了疫情。
And the pandemic was not since 1917, where 100 million people died.
这场疫情不是自1917年以来，导致数百万人死亡的那种。
Has there been anything like it?
有类似的情况吗？
We did a phenomenal job with the pandemic.
我们在疫情期间做得非常出色。
We handed them over a country where the economy and where the stock market was higher than it was before the pandemic came in.
我们交给了他们一个经济和股市都比疫情前更高的国家。
Nobody's ever seen anything like it.
没人见过这样的事情。
We made ventilators for the entire world.
我们为全世界制造了呼吸机。
We got gowns.
我们有礼服。
We got masks.
我们有口罩。
We did things that nobody thought possible.
我们做了一些没人认为可能的事情。
And people give me credit for rebuilding the military.
人们给我重建军队的功劳。
They give me credit for a lot of things, but not enough credit for the great job we did with the pandemic.
他们给我很多事情的功劳，但对我应对疫情做得出色的功劳还不够。
But the only jobs they got were bounce-back jobs.
但他们得到的只是反弹的工作。
These were jobs bounce-back, and it bounced back and it went to their benefit.
这些是反弹的工作，反弹了，对他们有利。
But I was the one that created them.
但我是创造这些工作的人。
They know it, and so does everybody else.
他们知道，其他人也知道。
Vice President Harris, I'll let you respond.
哈里斯副总统，我让你回应。
Donald Trump has no plan for you.
唐纳德·特朗普没有为你制定计划。
And when you look at his economic plan, it's all about tax breaks for the richest people.
当你看他的经济计划时，全是给最富有人群的税收减免。
I am offering what I describe as an opportunity economy, and the best economists in our country, if not the world, have reviewed our relative plans for the future of America.
我提供的是我称之为机会经济，我们国家最好的经济学家，如果不是全世界的话，已经审查了我们相对的未来计划。
What Goldman Sachs has said is that Donald Trump's plan would make the economy worse, mine would strengthen the economy.
高盛说，唐纳德·特朗普的计划会让经济更糟，我的会加强经济。
What the Wharton School has said is Donald Trump's plan would actually explode the deficit.
沃顿商学院说，唐纳德·特朗普的计划实际上会扩大赤字。
Sixteen Nobel laureates have described his economic plan as something that would increase inflation and by the middle of next year would invite a recession.
十六位诺贝尔奖得主形容他的经济计划会增加通胀，到明年中会引发衰退。
You just have to look at where we are and where we stand on the issues.
你只需要看看我们在哪里，我们在这些问题上的立场。
And I'd invite you to know that Donald Trump actually has no plan for you, because he is more interested in defending himself than he is in looking out for you.
我想让你知道，唐纳德·特朗普实际上没有为你制定计划，因为他更感兴趣的是为自己辩护，而不是为你着想。
It's just a soundbite.
这只是个口号。
They gave her that to say, look, I went to the Wharton School of Finance and many of those professors, the top professors think my plan is a brilliant plan.
他们让她这么说，看，我去了沃顿商学院，很多顶级教授认为我的计划很棒。
It's a great plan.
这是个伟大的计划。
It's a plan that's going to bring up our worth, our value as a country.
这是个会提升我们国家价值的计划。
It's going to make people want to be able to go and work and
会让人们想要去工作，
and create jobs and create a lot of good, solid money for our country.
创造工作，为我们国家创造很多好钱。
Just to finish off, she doesn't have a plan.
最后，她没有计划。
She copied Biden's plan, and it's like four sentences, like run, spot, run, four sentences that are just, oh, we'll try and lower taxes.
她抄袭了拜登的计划，就像四句话，跑，点，跑，四句话，哦，我们会尝试降低税收。
She doesn't have a plan.
她没有计划。
Take a look at her plan.
看看她的计划。
She doesn't have a plan.
她没有计划。
Mr. President, I do want to drill down on something you both brought up.
总统先生，我确实想深入探讨你们都提到的事情。
The Vice President brought up your tariffs.
副总统提到了你的关税政策。
You responded, and let's drill down on this, because your plan is what she calls is essentially a national sales tax.
你回应了，我们来深入探讨一下，因为你的计划在她看来本质上是一种国家销售税。
Your proposal calls for tariffs, as you pointed out here, on foreign imports across the board.
你的提议要求对所有外国进口商品征收关税，正如你在这里指出的那样。
You recently said that you might double your plan, imposing tariffs up to 20 percent on goods coming into this country.
你最近表示可能会将计划加倍，对进入我国的商品征收高达20%的关税。
As you know, many economists say that with tariffs at that level, costs are then passed on to the consumer.
如你所知，许多经济学家认为，在这样的关税水平下，成本会转嫁给消费者。
Vice President Harris has argued it'll mean higher prices on gas, food, clothing, medication, arguing it costs the typical family nearly $4,000 a year.
哈里斯副总统辩称，这将意味着汽油、食品、服装、药品的价格上涨，声称这使普通家庭每年多支出近4000美元。
Do you believe Americans can afford higher prices because of tariffs?
你认为美国人能承受因关税而上涨的价格吗？
They're not going to have higher prices.
他们不会面临更高的价格。
What's going to happen, who's going to have higher prices is China and all of the countries that have been ripping us off for years.
真正会面临更高价格的是中国和所有多年来一直在占我们便宜的国家。
I charge, I was the only president ever,
我征收了，我是唯一一个总统，
China is paying us hundreds of billions of dollars and so are other countries.
中国向我们支付了数千亿美元，其他国家也是如此。
billions of dollars, hundreds of billions of dollars.
数十亿美元，数百亿美元。
I had no inflation, virtually no inflation.
我没有通胀，几乎没有通胀。
They had the highest inflation, perhaps, in the history of our country, because I've never seen a worse period of time.
他们经历了可能是我国历史上最高的通胀，因为我从未见过如此糟糕的时期。
People can't go out and buy cereal or bacon or eggs or anything else.
人们无法外出购买麦片、培根、鸡蛋或其他任何东西。
These the people of our country are absolutely dying with what they've done.
我们国家的这些人民正因为他们的所作所为而痛苦不堪。
They've destroyed the economy.
他们摧毁了经济。
And all you have to do is look at a poll.
你只需要看一项民调。
The polls say 80 and 85 and even 90 percent that the Trump economy was great, that their economy was terrible.
民调显示，80%、85%甚至90%的人认为特朗普经济很好，而他们的经济很糟糕。
Vice President Harris, I do want to ask for your response.
哈里斯副总统，我想听听你的回应。
And you heard what the president said there, because the Biden administration did keep a number of the Trump tariffs in place.
你听到了总统刚才的话，因为拜登政府保留了许多特朗普时期的关税。
So how do you respond?
那么你如何回应？
Well, let's be clear that the Trump administration resulted in a trade deficit, one of the highest we've ever seen in the history of America.
好吧，让我们明确一点，特朗普政府导致了贸易逆差，这是美国历史上最高的之一。
He invited trade wars.
他引发了贸易战。
You want to talk about his deal with China, what he ended up doing is under Donald Trump's presidency, he ended up selling American chips
你想谈谈他与中国的协议，他最终在特朗普总统任期内，向中国出售了美国芯片，
to China to help them improve and modernize their military basically sold us out when a policy about China should be in making sure the United States of America wins the competition for the 21st century.
帮助他们改进和现代化军事，基本上是出卖了我们，而关于中国的政策应该是确保美国在21世纪的竞争中获胜。
which means focusing on the details of what that requires, focusing on relationships with our allies, focusing on investing in American-based technology so that we win the race on AI, on quantum computing, focusing on what we need to do to support America's workforce so that we don't end up having, on the short end of the stick,
这意味着要关注实现这一目标所需的细节，关注与盟友的关系，关注投资美国本土技术，以便我们在人工智能、量子计算方面取得胜利，关注我们需要做些什么来支持美国劳动力，以免我们在工人权益方面处于不利地位。
in terms of workers' rights.
但在工人权益方面。
But what Donald Trump did—let's talk about this—with COVID is he actually thanked President Xi for what he did during COVID.
但特朗普在COVID问题上——让我们谈谈这个——他实际上感谢了习近平主席在COVID期间所做的工作。
Look at his tweet.
看看他的推文。
Thank you, President Xi!
谢谢，习近平主席！
When we know that Xi was responsible for lacking and not giving us transparency about the origins of COVID.
当我们知道习近平对COVID的起源缺乏透明度，没有给我们提供信息时。
President Trump, I'll let you respond.
特朗普总统，我让你回应。
First of all, they bought their chips from Taiwan.
首先，他们从台湾购买芯片。
We hardly make chips anymore because of philosophies like they have and policies like they have.
由于他们的理念和政策，我们几乎不再制造芯片了。
I don't say her because she has no policy.
我不说她，因为她没有政策。
Everything that she believed three years ago and four years ago is out the window.
她三年前和四年前所相信的一切都已经过时了。
She's going to my philosophy now.
她现在转向了我的理念。
In fact, I was going to send her a MAGA hat.
事实上，我本来打算送她一顶MAGA帽子。
She's gone to my philosophy.
她已经转向了我的理念。
If she ever got elected, she'd change it, and it will be the end of our country.
如果她当选，她会改变这一切，那将是我国的末日。
She's a Marxist.
她是个马克思主义者。
Everybody knows she's a Marxist.
大家都知道她是个马克思主义者。
Her father's a Marxist professor in economics, and he taught her well.
她的父亲是经济学领域的马克思主义教授，他教得很好。
But when you look at what she's done to our country, and when you look at these millions and millions of people that are pouring into our country monthly, where it's, I believe, 21 million people, not the 15 that people say,
但当你看看她对我们国家做了什么，当你看看每个月涌入我国的数百万人，我相信是2100万人，而不是人们所说的1500万，
And I think it's a lot higher than the 21.
我认为比2100万还要多。
That's bigger than New York State pouring in.
这比纽约州的人口还要多。
And just look at what they're doing to our country.
看看他们对我国做了什么。
They're criminals.
他们是罪犯。
Many of these people coming in are criminals.
许多进来的人都是罪犯。
And that's bad for our economy, too.
这对我们的经济也不利。
You know, you mentioned before, we'll talk about immigration later.
你知道，你之前提到过，我们稍后再谈移民问题。
Well, bad immigration is the worst thing that can happen to our economy.
糟糕的移民政策是对我国经济最糟糕的事情。
They have, and she has, destroyed our country with policy that's insane.
他们和她用疯狂的政策摧毁了我们的国家。
Almost policy that you'd say they have to hate our country.
几乎可以说，他们的政策表明他们必须恨我们的国家。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
Lindsey?
林赛？
I want to turn to the issue of abortion.
我想转向堕胎问题。
President Trump, you've often touted that you were able to kill Roe v. Wade last year.
特朗普总统，你经常吹嘘去年你成功推翻了罗伊诉韦德案。
You said that you were proud to be the most pro-life president in American history.
你说你为自己是美国历史上最支持生命的总统而感到自豪。
Then last month, you said that your administration would be great for women and their reproductive rights.
上个月，你说你的政府将有利于女性及其生殖权利。
In your home state of Florida, you surprised many with regard to your six-week abortion ban, because you initially had said that it was too short.
在你的家乡佛罗里达州，你关于六周堕胎禁令的表态让很多人感到意外，因为你最初曾表示这个时间太短。
And you said, quote, I'm going to be voting that we need more than six weeks.
你当时说，“我会投票支持我们需要超过六周的时间。”
But then, the very next day, you reversed course and said you would vote to support the six-week ban.
但就在第二天，你改变了立场，表示你会投票支持六周禁令。
Vice President Harris says that women shouldn't trust you on the issue of abortion because you've changed your position so many times.
副总统哈里斯说，女性不应该信任你在堕胎问题上的立场，因为你已经多次改变立场。
Therefore, why should they trust you?
那么，她们为什么要信任你呢？
The reason I'm doing that vote is because the plan is, as you know, the voters, they have abortion in the ninth month.
我之所以那样投票，是因为你知道，选民们，他们在第九个月还有堕胎。
They even have and you can look at the governor of West Virginia, the previous governor of West Virginia, not the current governor is doing an excellent job, but the governor before he said
他们甚至有，你可以看看西弗吉尼亚州的州长，前州长，不是现任州长，现任州长做得很好，但之前的州长说
The baby will be born, and we will decide what to do with the baby.
孩子将会出生，我们将决定如何处理这个孩子。
In other words, we'll execute the baby.
换句话说，我们会处决这个孩子。
And that's why I did that, because that predominates.
这就是我那样做的原因，因为那占主导地位。
Because they're radical.
因为他们是激进的。
The Democrats are radical in that.
民主党在那方面是激进的。
And her vice presidential pick, which I think is a horrible pick, by the way, for our country, because he is really out of it.
她的副总统人选，顺便说一句，我认为这对我们的国家来说是一个可怕的选择，因为他真的不在状态。
But her vice presidential pick says abortion in the ninth month is absolutely fine.
但她的副总统人选说，第九个月的堕胎绝对没问题。
He also says execution after birth, it's execution, no longer abortion because the baby is born, is okay.
他还说，出生后的处决，不再是堕胎，因为孩子已经出生，是可以的。
And that's not okay with me, hence the vote.
这对我来说不行，因此我投了票。
But what I did is something for
但我所做的是为了
52 years they've been trying to get Roe v. Wade into the states.
52年来他们一直在试图将罗伊诉韦德案纳入各州。
And through the genius and heart and strength of six Supreme Court justices, we were able to do that.
通过六位最高法院大法官的智慧、心和力量，我们做到了。
Now, I believe in the exceptions for
现在，我相信在
rape, incest, and life of the mother.
强奸、乱伦和母亲生命的情况下有例外。
I believe strongly in it.
我对此深信不疑。
Ronald Reagan did also.
罗纳德·里根也这样认为。
Eighty-five percent of Republicans do.
85%的共和党人也是如此。
Exceptions.
例外。
Very important.
非常重要。
But we were able to get it, and now states are voting on it.
但我们做到了，现在各州正在对此进行投票。
And for the first time, you're going to see — look, this is an issue that's torn our country apart for 52 years.
这是第一次，你会看到——看，这是一个撕裂我们国家52年的问题。
Every legal scholar, every Democrat, every Republican, liberal, conservative, they all wanted this issue to be brought back to the states where the people could vote.
每一位法律学者，每一位民主党人，每一位共和党人，自由派，保守派，他们都希望这个问题能回到各州，让人民投票。
And that's what happened.
事情就是这样发生的。
Now, Ohio, the vote was somewhat liberal.
现在，俄亥俄州的投票有些自由派倾向。
Kansas, the vote was somewhat liberal, much more liberal than people would have thought.
堪萨斯州的投票也有些自由派倾向，比人们想象的要自由得多。
But each individual state
但每个州
is voting.
都在投票。
It's the vote of the people now.
现在是人民的投票。
It's not tied up in the federal government.
这不再受联邦政府控制。
I did a great service in doing it.
我这样做是做出了巨大的贡献。
It took courage to do it.
这样做需要勇气。
And the Supreme Court had great courage in doing it.
最高法院在这件事上表现出了极大的勇气。
And I give tremendous credit to those six justices.
我非常感谢那六位大法官。
There is no state in this country where it is legal to kill a baby after it's born.
在这个国家的任何州，杀死一个已经出生的婴儿都是违法的。
Madam Vice President, I want to get your response to President Trump.
副总统女士，我想听听您对特朗普总统的回应。
Well, as I said, you're going to hear a bunch of lies, and that's not actually a surprising fact.
正如我所说，你会听到一堆谎言，这并不令人意外。
Let's understand how we got here.
让我们了解一下我们是如何走到这一步的。
Donald Trump hand-selected three members of the United States Supreme Court with the intention that they would undo the protections of Roe v. Wade.
唐纳德·特朗普亲自挑选了三位美国最高法院的成员，意图让他们推翻罗伊诉韦德案的保护措施。
And they did exactly as he intended.
他们确实如他所愿。
And now in over 20 states, there are Trump abortion bans, which make it criminal for a doctor or nurse to provide health care.
现在在超过20个州，有特朗普的堕胎禁令，这使得医生或护士提供医疗服务成为犯罪。
In one state, it provides prison for life.
在一个州，这可能导致终身监禁。
Trump abortion bans that make no exception even for rape and incest, which understand what that means.
特朗普的堕胎禁令没有任何例外，即使是强奸和乱伦，这意味着什么。
A survivor of a crime, a violation to their body, does not have the right to make a decision about what happens to their body next.
犯罪的受害者，身体受到侵犯，没有权利决定接下来对自己身体做什么。
That is immoral.
这是不道德的。
And one does not have to abandon their faith or deeply held beliefs to agree.
人们不必放弃自己的信仰或深信的信念来同意这一点。
The government, and Donald Trump certainly, should not be telling a woman what to do with her body.
政府，尤其是唐纳德·特朗普，不应该告诉一个女人如何处理自己的身体。
I have talked with women around our country.
我和全国各地的女性谈过。
You want to talk about this is what people wanted?
你想谈论人们想要什么吗？
Pregnant women who want to carry a pregnancy to term, suffering from a miscarriage, being denied care in an emergency room because the health care providers are afraid they might go to jail, and she's bleeding out in a car in the parking lot.
想要继续怀孕的孕妇，因流产而痛苦，在急诊室被拒绝治疗，因为医护人员害怕可能会被判入狱，而她在停车场的车里流血不止。
She didn't want that.
她不想要那样。
Her husband didn't want that.
她的丈夫也不想要那样。
A 12 or 13-year-old survivor of incest being forced to carry a pregnancy to term.
一个12或13岁的乱伦受害者被迫继续怀孕。
They don't want that.
他们不想要那样。
And I pledge to you, when Congress passes a bill to put back in place the protections of Roe v. Wade as President of the United States, I will proudly sign it into law.
我向你们保证，当国会通过一项法案，恢复罗伊诉韦德案的保护时，作为美国总统，我将自豪地将其签署为法律。
But understand, if Donald Trump were to be reelected, he will sign a national abortion ban.
但请理解，如果唐纳德·特朗普再次当选，他将签署一项全国性的堕胎禁令。
Understand, in his Project 2025, there would be a national abortion monitor that would be monitoring your pregnancies, your miscarriages.
请理解，在他的2025计划中，将会有一个全国性的堕胎监控机构，监控你们的怀孕和流产情况。
I think the American people believe
我认为美国人民相信
that certain freedoms, in particular the freedom to make decisions about one's own body, should not be made by the government.
某些自由，特别是关于个人身体决定的自由，不应由政府来决定。
Thank you, Vice President Harris.
谢谢你，副总统哈里斯。
Well, there she goes again.
好吧，她又来了。
It's a lie.
这是谎言。
I'm not signing a ban and there's no reason to sign a ban because
我不会签署禁令，也没有理由签署禁令，因为
We've gotten what everybody wanted.
我们已经得到了所有人都想要的。
Democrats, Republicans, and everybody else, and every legal scholar wanted it to be brought back into the states.
民主党人、共和党人，以及其他所有人，所有法律学者都希望将其交还给各州。
And the states are voting.
各州正在投票。
And it may take a little time.
这可能需要一点时间。
But for 52 years, this issue has torn our country apart.
但52年来，这个问题一直撕裂着我们的国家。
And they've wanted it back in the states.
他们希望将其交还给各州。
And I did something that nobody thought was possible.
我做了一件没人认为可能的事情。
The states are now voting.
各州现在正在投票。
What she says is an absolute lie.
她说的完全是谎言。
And as far as the abortion ban, no, I'm not in favor of abortion ban, but it doesn't matter because this issue has now been taken over by the states.
至于堕胎禁令，不，我不赞成堕胎禁令，但这无关紧要，因为这个问题现在已经由各州接管。
Would you veto a national abortion ban if it came to your desk?
如果全国性的堕胎禁令送到你的办公桌上，你会否决吗？
Well, I won't have to because, again, two things.
好吧，我不需要这样做，因为，再说两件事。
Number one, she said she'll go back to Congress.
第一，她说她会回到国会。
She'll never get the vote.
她永远得不到投票。
It's impossible for her to get the vote, especially now with the 50-50, essentially 50-50 in both Senate and the House.
她不可能得到投票，尤其是在参众两院基本上50-50的情况下。
She's not going to get the vote.
她得不到投票。
She can't get the vote.
她无法得到投票。
She won't even come close to it.
她甚至不会接近。
So it's just talk.
所以这只是空谈。
You know what it reminds me of?
你知道这让我想起了什么吗？
When they said they're going to get student loans terminated, and it ended up being a total catastrophe.
他们说要取消学生贷款，结果却变成了一场灾难。
This is
这
taunted with this whole thing about this whole idea and how unfair that would have been part of the reason they lost to The millions and millions of people that had to pay off their student loans.
被整个事情嘲弄，关于这个想法以及它有多不公平，部分原因是他们失去了数百万需要偿还学生贷款的人。
They didn't get it for free But they were saying it's the same way that they talked about that that they talk about abortion.
他们没有免费得到，但他们说这是他们谈论堕胎的方式。
But if I could just get a yes or no, because you're running me, J.D.
但如果我能得到一个是或否的答案，因为你正在让我，J.D.
Vance has said that you would veto if it did come to your desk.
Vance说过，如果它真的到了你的办公桌上，你会否决。
Well, I didn't discuss it with J.D.
嗯，我没有和J.D.讨论过。
In all fairness, J.D., and I don't mind if he has a certain view, but I think he was speaking for me, but I really didn't.
公平地说，J.D.，我不介意他有一些特定的观点，但我认为他是在为我说话，但我真的没有。
We don't have to discuss it, because she'd never be able to get it.
我们不必讨论，因为她永远无法得到它。
Just like she couldn't get student loans, they couldn't get student loans.
就像她无法得到学生贷款一样，他们也无法得到学生贷款。
They didn't even come close to getting student loans.
他们甚至没有接近得到学生贷款。
They taunted young people and a lot of other people that had loans.
他们嘲弄了有贷款的年轻人和其他许多人。
They can never get this approved.
他们永远无法获得批准。
So it doesn't matter what she says about going to Congress.
所以她关于去国会的事情无关紧要。
Oh, wonderful.
哦，太好了。
Let's go to Congress.
让我们去国会。
Do it.
去做吧。
But the fact is that for years, they wanted to get it out of Congress and out of the federal government.
但事实是多年来，他们想把它从国会和联邦政府中拿出来。
And we did something that everybody said couldn't be done.
而我们做了一件大家都说不可能的事。
And now you have a vote of the people on abortion.
现在你有了关于堕胎的民意投票。
Vice President Harris, I want to give you your time to respond, but I do want to ask, would you support any restrictions on a woman's right to an abortion?
副总统哈里斯，我想给你时间回应，但我确实想问，你会支持对女性堕胎权利的任何限制吗？
I absolutely support reinstating the protections of Roe v. Wade, and as you rightly mentioned, nowhere in America
我绝对支持恢复罗伊诉韦德案的保护，正如你正确提到的，在美国任何地方
is a woman carrying a pregnancy to term and asking for an abortion.
没有一个女人怀孕到足月并要求堕胎。
That is not happening.
那没有发生。
It's insulting to the women of America.
这对美国女性是一种侮辱。
And understand what has been happening under Donald Trump's abortion bans.
并理解在唐纳德·特朗普的堕胎禁令下发生了什么。
Couples who pray and dream of having a family are being denied IVF treatments.
祈祷并梦想拥有家庭的夫妇被拒绝接受试管婴儿治疗。
What is happening in our country?
我们国家发生了什么？
Working people, working women who are working one or two jobs, who can barely afford child care as it is, have to travel to another state to get on a plane sitting next to strangers to go and get the health care she needs.
工作的人，工作的女性，她们做一份或两份工作，几乎负担不起现有的托儿费用，不得不去另一个州，坐在陌生人旁边上飞机，去获得她需要的医疗保健。
barely can afford to do it, and what you are putting her through is unconscionable.
几乎负担不起，而你让她经历的是不可原谅的。
And the people of America have not—the majority of Americans believe in a woman's right to make decisions about her own body, and that is why, in every state where this issue has been on the ballot, in red and blue states both, the people of America have voted for freedom.
大多数美国人相信女性有权决定自己的身体，这就是为什么在每个州，无论是红色州还是蓝色州，当这个问题被提上议程时，美国人民都投票支持自由。
vice president
副总统
I saw the people of Alabama and the legislature two days later voted it in.
我看到阿拉巴马州的人民和立法机构两天后投票通过了。
I've been a leader on it.
我一直是这方面的领导者。
They know that and everybody else knows it.
他们知道这一点，其他人也知道。
I have been a leader on fertilization IVF.
我在体外受精方面一直是领导者。
And the other thing, they, you should ask, will she allow abortion in the eighth month, ninth month, seventh month?
还有一件事，你应该问，她是否允许在第八个月、第九个月、第七个月进行堕胎？
Come on.
得了吧。
Okay, would you do that?
你会那样做吗？
Why don't you ask her that question?
你为什么不问她这个问题？
That's the problem.
这就是问题所在。
Because under Roe v. Wade, you could do abortions in the seventh month, the eighth month, the ninth month, and probably after birth.
因为在罗伊诉韦德案中，你可以在第七个月、第八个月、第九个月进行堕胎，甚至可能在出生后。
Just look at the governor, former governor of Virginia.
看看弗吉尼亚州的前州长。
The governor of Virginia said we put the baby aside and then we determine what we want to do with the baby.
弗吉尼亚州的州长说，我们先把婴儿放在一边，然后我们决定对婴儿做什么。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢你。
We're going to turn now to immigration and border security.
我们现在转向移民和边境安全问题。
We know it's an issue that's important to Republicans, Democrats, voters across the board in this country.
我们知道这是一个对共和党人、民主党人以及全国各地选民都很重要的问题。
Vice President Harris, you were tasked by President Biden with getting to the root causes of migration from Central America.
哈里斯副总统，拜登总统指派你解决中美洲移民的根本原因。
We know that illegal border crossings reached a record high in the Biden administration.
我们知道在拜登政府期间，非法越境达到了历史新高。
This past June, President Biden imposed tough new asylum restrictions.
今年六月，拜登总统实施了新的严格的庇护限制。
We know the numbers since then have dropped significantly.
我们知道自那以后，数字显著下降。
But my question to you tonight is, why did the administration wait until six months before the election to act?
但我今晚的问题是，为什么政府要等到选举前六个月才采取行动？
And would you have done anything differently from President Biden on this?
你会在这方面与拜登总统有所不同吗？
So I'm the only person on this stage who has prosecuted transnational criminal organizations for the trafficking of guns, drugs and human beings.
我是这个舞台上唯一一个曾起诉跨国犯罪组织进行枪支、毒品和人贩运的人。
And let me say that the United States Congress, including some of the most conservative members of the United States Senate, came up with a border security bill, which I supported.
让我说，美国国会，包括美国参议院中一些最保守的成员，提出了一项边境安全法案，我支持这项法案。
And that bill would have put 1,500 more border agents on the border to help those folks who are working there right now, over time, trying to do their job.
该法案将在边境增加1500名边境特工，帮助那些现在正在努力工作的人，随着时间的推移，试图完成他们的工作。
It would have allowed us to stem the flow of fentanyl coming into the United States.
这将使我们能够遏制芬太尼流入美国。
I know there are so many families watching tonight who have been personally affected
我知道今晚有很多家庭在观看，他们个人受到了我国芬太尼激增的影响。
by the surge of fentanyl in our country.
该法案将提供更多资源，使我们能够起诉跨国犯罪组织进行枪支、毒品和人贩运。
That bill would have put more resources to allow us to prosecute transnational criminal organizations for trafficking in guns, drugs, and human beings.
But you know what happened to that bill?
但你知道那项法案发生了什么吗？
Donald Trump got on the phone, called up some folks in Congress, and said, kill the bill.
唐纳德·特朗普打电话给国会的一些人，说，干掉那项法案。
And you know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because he'd prefer to run on a problem instead of fixing a problem.
因为他宁愿在问题上做文章，而不是解决问题。
And understand, this comes at a time where the people of our country actually need a leader who engages in solutions, who actually addresses the problems at hand.
要明白，这发生在我们国家的人民真正需要一个能解决问题、真正解决当前问题的领导者的时候。
But what we have in the former president is someone who would prefer to run on a problem instead of fixing a problem.
但我们从前总统那里得到的，是一个宁愿在问题上做文章而不是解决问题的人。
And I'll tell you something, he's going to talk about immigration a lot tonight, even when it's not the subject that is being raised.
我告诉你，他今晚会在移民问题上大做文章，即使这不是正在讨论的话题。
And I'm going to actually do something really unusual, and I'm going to invite you to attend one of Donald Trump's rallies, because it's a really interesting thing to watch.
我打算做一件非常不寻常的事，我邀请你去参加唐纳德·特朗普的集会，因为那真的很有趣。
You will see during the course of his rallies, he talks about fictional characters like Hannibal Lecter.
你会在他的集会上看到，他会谈论像汉尼拔·莱克特这样的虚构人物。
He will talk about when mills cause cancer.
他会谈论工厂如何导致癌症。
And what you will also notice is that people start leaving his rallies early, out of exhaustion and boredom.
你还会注意到，人们会因为疲惫和无聊而早早离开他的集会。
And I will tell you, the one thing you will not hear him talk about is you.
我告诉你，你不会听到他谈论你。
You will not hear him talk about your needs, your dreams, and your desires.
你不会听到他谈论你的需求、你的梦想和你的愿望。
And I'll tell you, I believe you deserve a president who actually puts you first, and I pledge to you that I will.
我告诉你，我相信你值得一个真正把你放在首位的总统，我向你保证我会做到。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
副总统哈里斯，谢谢你。
President Trump, on that point, I want to get your response.
特朗普总统，关于这一点，我想听听你的回应。
Well, I would like to respond.
我愿意回应。
Let me just ask, though, why did you try to kill that bill, and successfully so, that would have put thousands of additional agents and officers on the border?
不过，我想问，你为什么要试图扼杀那项法案，而且成功了，那项法案本可以让数千名额外的特工和官员驻守边境？
First let me respond is to the rallies.
首先让我回应集会的问题。
She said people start leaving.
她说人们开始离开。
People don't go to her rallies.
人们不去她的集会。
There's no reason to go.
没有理由去。
And the people that do go, she's bussing them in and paying them to be there, and then showing them in a different light.
那些去的人，她用巴士把他们送来，付钱让他们去，然后以不同的方式展示他们。
So she can't talk about that.
所以她不能谈论这个。
People don't leave my rallies.
人们不会离开我的集会。
We have the biggest rallies, the most incredible rallies in the history of politics.
我们有史上最大的集会，最不可思议的集会。
That's because people want to take their country back.
那是因为人们想夺回他们的国家。
Our country is being lost.
我们的国家正在失去。
We're a failing nation.
我们是一个失败的国家。
And it happened three and a half years ago.
这发生在三年半前。
And what's going on here, you're going to end up in World War III, just to go into another subject.
他们通过允许这些成千上万的人进入我们的国家，对我们国家做了什么，看看全美各地的城镇发生了什么。
what they have done to our country by allowing these millions and millions of people to come into our country and look at what's happening to the towns all over the United States.
很多城镇不想谈论这件事。
And a lot of towns don't want to talk.
不会是奥罗拉或斯普林菲尔德。
It's not going to be Aurora or Springfield.
很多城镇不想谈论这件事，因为他们对此感到非常尴尬。
A lot of towns don't want to talk about it because they're so embarrassed by it.
在斯普林菲尔德，那些来的人在吃狗。
In Springfield, they're eating the dogs, the people that came in.
他们在吃猫。
They're eating the cats.
他们在吃
They're eating
他们在吃住在那里的人的宠物。
They're eating the pets of the people that live there.
这就是我们国家正在发生的事情。
And this is what's happening in our country.
这是可耻的。
And it's a shame.
至于集会，至于——他们去的原因是他们喜欢我说的话。
As far as rallies are concerned, as far as — the reason they go is they like what I say.
他们想把我们的国家带回来。
They want to bring our country back.
他们想让美国再次伟大。
They want to make America great again.
这是一个非常简单的口号——让美国再次伟大。
It's a very simple phrase — make America great again.
她在摧毁这个国家，如果她成为总统，这个国家就没有成功的机会。
She's destroying this country, and if she becomes president, this country doesn't have a chance of success.
不仅是成功，我们最终会变成打了兴奋剂的委内瑞拉。
Not only success, we'll end up being Venezuela on steroids.
我只是想在这里澄清一下。
I just want to clarify here.
你提到斯普林菲尔德，俄亥俄州，ABC新闻确实联系了那里的城市经理。
You bring up Springfield, Ohio, and ABC News did reach out to the city manager there.
他告诉我们，没有可信的报告表明移民社区中有人伤害、伤害或虐待宠物。
He told us there had been no credible reports of specific claims of pets being harmed, injured, or abused by individuals within the immigrant community.
嗯，我在电视上看到过人们。
Well, I've seen people on television.
电视上的人说我的狗被带走并被用作食物。
The people on television say my dog was taken and used for food.
所以也许他这么说了，也许这对城市经理来说是个好事。
So maybe he said that, and maybe that's a good thing to say for a city manager.
我不是从电视上得到这个信息的。
I'm not taking this from television.
但电视上的人说我的狗被去那里的人吃了。
But the people on television say my dog was eaten by the people that went there.
再次，斯普林菲尔德的城市经理说没有证据表明这一点。
Again, the Springfield city manager says there's no evidence of that.
哈里斯副总统，我让你回应你听到的其余部分。
Vice President Harris, I'll let you respond to the rest of what you've heard.
你谈到极端。
You talk about extreme.
我认为这是为什么，在这次选举中，我实际上得到了200名共和党人的支持，他们曾正式与布什总统、米特·罗姆尼和约翰·麦凯恩共事，包括前副总统迪克·切尼和国会议员利兹·切尼的支持。
This is, I think, one of the reasons why, in this election, I actually have the endorsement of 200 Republicans who have formally worked with President Bush, Mitt Romney, and John McCain, including the endorsement of former Vice President Dick Cheney and Congress member Liz Cheney.
如果你想真正了解前总统是谁，如果他还没有说清楚，就问问那些和他共事过的人。
And if you want to really know the inside track on who the former president is, if he didn't make it clear already, just ask people who have worked with him.
[Translation missing line - 30]
His former chief of staff, a four-star general, has said he has contempt for the Constitution of the United States.
他的前幕僚长，一位四星上将，曾表示他对美国宪法不屑一顾。
His former national security advisor has said he is dangerous and unfit.
他的前国家安全顾问称他危险且不适合担任职务。
His former Secretary of Defense has said the nation, the republic, would never survive another Trump term.
他的前国防部长表示，国家，共和国，无法再承受特朗普的又一个任期。
And when we listen to this kind of rhetoric, when the issues that affect the American people are not being addressed, I think the choice is clear in this election.
当我们听到这种言论时，当影响美国人民的问题没有得到解决时，我认为这次选举的选择是显而易见的。
President Trump will give you a quick minute to respond.
特朗普总统，给你一分钟时间回应。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Because when I hear that, see, I'm a different kind of a person.
因为当我听到这些，你看，我是个不同类型的人。
I fired most of those people.
我把那些人都炒了。
Not so graciously.
不是那么客气地。
They did bad things or a bad job.
他们做了坏事或做得不好。
I fired them.
我把他们炒了。
They never fired one person.
他们一个也没炒。
They didn't fire anybody having to do with Afghanistan and the Taliban and the 13 people who's who's
他们没有解雇任何与阿富汗和塔利班有关的人，以及那13个刚刚被残忍杀害的人。
were just killed, viciously and violently killed.
我认识他们的父母和家人。
And I got to know the parents and the family.
他们没有解雇。
They didn't fire.
他们应该解雇所有那些将军，所有那些高层人员，因为那是任何人见过的最无能的处理方式之一。
They should have fired all those generals, all those top people, because that was one of the most incompetently handled situations anybody has ever seen.
所以当有人做得不好时，我就会炒了他。
So when somebody does a bad job, I fire him.
你看看像埃斯珀这样的人。
And you take a guy like Esper.
他不行。
He was no good.
我把他炒了。
I fired him.
所以他写了一本书。
So he writes a book.
另一个也写了一本书。
Another one writes a book.
因为对我来说，他们可以写书。
Because with me, they can write books.
对其他人，他们不行。
With nobody else can they.
但他们做得太差了，他们从来没有解雇过任何人。
But they have done such a poor job, and they never fire anybody.
看看经济。
Look at the economy.
看看通货膨胀。
Look at the inflation.
他们没有解雇任何经济学家。
They didn't fire any of their economists.
他们还是那些人。
They have the same people.
That's a good way not to have books written about you.
这是避免被人写书的最好方法。
But just to finish, I got more votes than any Republican in history by far.
但为了结束这个话题，我获得的选票比历史上任何一位共和党人都多得多。
In fact, I got more votes than any president, sitting president, in history by far.
事实上，我获得的选票比历史上任何一位现任总统都多得多。
Let me continue on immigration.
让我继续谈谈移民问题。
It was what you wanted to talk about earlier.
这是你之前想谈的。
So let's get back to your deportation proposal that the vice president has reacted to as well.
所以让我们回到你的驱逐提案，副总统对此也有反应。
President Trump, you call this the largest domestic deportation operation in the history of our country.
特朗普总统，你称之为我国历史上最大的国内驱逐行动。
You say you would use the National Guard.
你说你会动用国民警卫队。
You say if things get out of control, you'd have no problem using the U.S.
你说如果情况失控，你不会介意动用美国军队。
military.
军队。
You also said you would use local police.
你还说你会动用当地警察。
How would you deport 11 million undocumented immigrants?
你将如何驱逐1100万无证移民？
I know you believe that number is much higher.
我知道你认为这个数字要高得多。
Take us through this.
给我们详细解释一下。
What does this look like?
这会是什么样子？
Will authorities be going door to door in this country?
当局会挨家挨户地在这个国家进行吗？
Yeah, it is much higher because of them.
是的，因为他们的原因，这个数字要高得多。
They allowed criminals, many, many millions of criminals.
他们允许罪犯，许多许多的罪犯。
They allowed terrorists.
他们允许恐怖分子。
They allowed common street criminals.
他们允许普通的街头罪犯。
They allowed people to come in, drug dealers to come into our country.
他们允许人们，包括毒贩，进入我们的国家。
And then now in the United States and told by their countries like Venezuela,
而现在在美国，被委内瑞拉等国家告知，
Don't ever come back or we're going to kill you.
永远不要回来，否则我们会杀了你。
Do you know that crime in Venezuela and crime in countries all over the world is way down?
你知道委内瑞拉和世界各地的犯罪率大幅下降吗？
You know why?
你知道为什么吗？
Because they've taken their criminals off the street and they've given them to her to put into our country.
因为他们把罪犯从街上带走，把他们交给她，让她把他们带进我们的国家。
And this will be one of the greatest mistakes in history for them to allow, and I think they probably did it because they think they're going to get votes, but it's not worth it.
这将是对他们来说历史上最大的错误之一，我认为他们可能这样做是因为他们认为会得到选票，但这不值得。
because they're destroying the fabric of our country by what they've done.
因为他们所做的正在摧毁我们国家的根基。
There's never been anything done like this at all.
从来没有做过这样的事情。
They've destroyed the fabric of our country.
他们摧毁了我们国家的根基。
Millions of people let in.
放进了数百万人。
And all over the world, crime is down all over the world except here.
世界各地的犯罪率都在下降，除了这里。
Crime here is up and through the roof.
这里的犯罪率却在飙升。
Despite their fraudulent statements that they made, crime in this country is through the roof.
尽管他们发表了虚假声明，但这个国家的犯罪率依然居高不下。
And we have a new form of crime.
我们面临一种新型犯罪。
It's called migrant crime.
叫做移民犯罪。
And it's happening at levels that nobody thought possible.
其规模超出了所有人的想象。
President Trump, as you know, the FBI says overall violent crime is actually coming down in this country, but Vice President Harris... Excuse me, the FBI defraud... They were defrauding statements.
特朗普总统，如你所知，FBI表示全国暴力犯罪率实际上在下降，但哈里斯副总统……抱歉，FBI在欺诈……他们的声明是欺诈性的。
They didn't include the worst cities.
他们没有包括犯罪最严重的城市。
They didn't include the cities with the worst crime.
他们没有包括犯罪率最高的城市。
It was a fraud, just like their number of 818,000 jobs that they said they created turned out to be a fraud.
这就是欺诈，就像他们声称创造了81.8万个工作岗位一样，结果也是欺诈。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
I'll let you respond, Vice President Harris.
我会让你回应，哈里斯副总统。
Well, I think this is so rich, coming from someone who has been prosecuted.
嗯，我觉得这很有趣，来自一个被起诉的人。
for national security crimes, economic crimes, election interference, has been found liable for sexual assault, and his next big court appearance is in November at his own criminal sentencing.
因国家安全犯罪、经济犯罪、选举干预被起诉，被判性侵罪名成立，下一次大法庭露面是在十一月，他自己的刑事判决。
And let's be clear where each person stands on the issue of what is important about respect for the rule of law and respect for law enforcement.
让我们明确每个人在尊重法治和执法问题上的立场。
The former vice president called for defunding federal law enforcement, 45,000 agents, get this, on the day after he was arraigned on 34 felony counts.
前副总统呼吁削减联邦执法经费，4.5万名特工，就在他被起诉34项重罪的第二天。
So let's talk about what is important in this race.
所以让我们谈谈这场竞选中什么才是重要的。
It is important that we move forward, that we turn the page on this same old tired rhetoric and address the needs of the American people, address what we need to do about the housing shortage, which I have a plan for, address what we must do to support our small businesses, address bringing down the price of groceries.
重要的是我们要前进，翻过这陈旧乏味的言论，解决美国人民的需求，解决我们面临的住房短缺问题，我有一个计划，解决我们必须支持小企业的问题，解决降低食品价格的问题。
But, frankly, the American people are exhausted with the same old tired playbook.
但坦白说，美国人民已经厌倦了这陈旧的剧本。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢。
Excuse me.
抱歉。
Every one of those cases was started by them against their political opponent.
每一起案件都是他们针对政治对手发起的。
And I'm winning most of them, and I will win the rest on appeal.
我大部分都赢了，剩下的我会在上诉中获胜。
And you saw that with the decision that came down just recently from the Supreme Court.
你看到了最近最高法院的裁决。
I'm winning most of them.
我大部分都赢了。
But those are cases, it's called weaponization, never happened in this country.
但那些案件，叫做武器化，这个国家从未发生过。
They weaponized the Justice Department.
他们武器化了司法部。
Every one of those cases was involved with the DOJ, from Atlanta and Fawny Willis to the Attorney General of New York and the DA in New York.
每一起案件都涉及司法部，从亚特兰大和方妮·威利斯到纽约的总检察长和地方检察官。
Every one of those cases.
每一起案件。
And then they say, oh, he's a criminal.
然后他们说，哦，他是个罪犯。
They're the ones that made them go after me.
是他们逼迫他们来对付我的。
By the way, Joe Biden was found essentially guilty on the documents case.
顺便说一下，乔·拜登在文件案中被判基本上有罪。
Now, what happened in my documents case?
那么，在我的文件案中发生了什么？
They said, oh, that's the toughest of them all.
他们说，哦，这是最难的一个。
a complete and total victory.
这是一个完全彻底的胜利。
Two months ago, it was thrown out.
两个月前，它被驳回了。
It's weaponization, and they used it, and it's never happened in this country.
这是武器化，他们用了它，这在我国从未发生过。
They used it to try and win an election.
他们用它来试图赢得选举。
They're fake cases.
这些都是假案。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢你。
A really quick response here, Vice President Harris, on this notion of weaponization of the Justice Department.
副总统哈里斯，关于司法部武器化的说法，请给出一个快速的回应。
Well, let's talk about extreme and understand the context in which this election in 2024 is taking place.
好吧，让我们谈谈极端，并理解2024年这场选举的背景。
The United States Supreme Court recently ruled that the former president would essentially be immune from any misconduct if he were to enter the White House again.
美国最高法院最近裁定，如果前总统再次入主白宫，他将基本上免于任何不当行为的指控。
Understand this is someone who has openly said he would terminate, I'm quoting, terminate the Constitution of the United States.
要知道，这个人曾公开表示他会终止，我引用一下，终止美国宪法。
That he would weaponize the Department of Justice against his political enemies.
他会利用司法部对付他的政治敌人。
Someone who has openly expressed disdain
这个人曾公开表达对
for members of our military.
我们军人的蔑视。
Understand what it would mean if Donald Trump were back in the White House with no guardrails.
要知道，如果唐纳德·特朗普在没有约束的情况下重返白宫，这意味着什么。
Because certainly we know now the court won't stop him.
因为现在我们肯定知道法院不会阻止他。
We know J.D.
我们知道J.D.
Vance is not going to stop him.
万斯不会阻止他。
It's up to the American people.
这取决于美国人民。
Vice President Harris.
副总统哈里斯。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Lindsey?
林赛？
Vice President Harris, in your last run for president.
副总统哈里斯，在你上次竞选总统时。
This is the one that weaponized, not me.
这是武器化的，不是我。
She weaponized.
是她武器化的。
I probably took a bullet to the head because of the things that they say about me.
我可能因为他们的言论而遭受了打击。
They talk about democracy.
他们谈论民主。
I'm a threat to democracy.
我是民主的威胁。
They're the threat to democracy with a fake Russia, Russia, Russia investigation that went nowhere.
他们才是民主的威胁，搞了个假的俄罗斯、俄罗斯、俄罗斯调查，结果一无所获。
We have a lot to get to.
我们有很多要讨论的。
Lindsey?
林赛？
Vice President Harris, in your last run for president, you said you wanted to ban fracking.
哈里斯副总统，您上次竞选总统时，曾表示想要禁止水力压裂法。
Now you don't.
现在您不这么想了。
You wanted mandatory government buyback programs for assault weapons.
您曾主张强制政府回购攻击性武器。
Now your campaign says you don't.
现在您的竞选团队说您不这么想了。
You supported decriminalizing border crossings.
您支持非刑事化边境穿越。
Now you're taking a harder line.
现在您采取了更严厉的立场。
I know you say that your values have not changed.
我知道您说您的价值观没有改变。
So then why have so many of your policy positions changed?
那么为什么您的许多政策立场都改变了呢？
So my values have not changed, and I'm going to discuss every one of the – at least every point that you've made.
所以我的价值观没有改变，我会逐一讨论——至少是您提到的每一点。
But in particular, let's talk about fracking, because we're here in Pennsylvania.
但特别地，让我们谈谈水力压裂法，因为我们现在在宾夕法尼亚州。
I made that very clear in 2020.
我在2020年已经说得很清楚了。
I will not ban fracking.
我不会禁止水力压裂法。
I have not banned fracking as vice president of the United States.
我作为美国副总统并没有禁止水力压裂法。
And in fact, I was the tie-breaking vote on the Inflation Reduction Act, which opened new leases for fracking.
事实上，我在《通胀削减法案》中投了关键一票，该法案为水力压裂法开辟了新的租赁。
My position is that we have got to invest in diverse sources of energy so we reduce our reliance on foreign oil.
我的立场是我们必须投资于多样化的能源来源，以减少对外国石油的依赖。
We have had the largest increase in domestic oil production in history because of an approach that recognizes that we cannot over-rely on foreign oil.
由于认识到我们不能过度依赖外国石油，我们实现了历史上国内石油产量的最大增长。
As it relates to my values, let me tell you, I grew up a middle-class kid raised by a hardworking mother.
至于我的价值观，让我告诉您，我是在一个努力工作的母亲抚养下长大的中产阶级孩子。
who worked and saved and was able to buy our first home when I was a teenager.
她工作、储蓄，并在我十几岁时为我们买了第一套房子。
The values I bring to the importance of home ownership, knowing not everybody got handed $400 million on a silver platter and then filed bankruptcy six times.
我带来的价值观是关于房屋所有权的重要性，知道不是每个人都能在银盘上得到4亿美元，然后六次破产。
is a value that I bring to my work to say we are going to work with the private sector and home builders to increase 3 million homes, increase by 3 million homes by the end of my first term.
这是我带到工作中的一种价值观，即我们将与私营部门和房屋建筑商合作，到我第一任期结束时增加300万套住房。
My work that is related to having a friend when I was in high school who was sexually assaulted by her stepfather.
我的工作与我在高中时的一个朋友有关，她被她的继父性侵。
And my focus then on protecting women and children from violent crime is based on a value that is deeply grounded in the importance of standing up for those who are most vulnerable.
我当时的重点是保护妇女和儿童免受暴力犯罪，这是基于一种深深植根于保护最弱势群体的重要性的价值观。
My work that is about protecting Social Security and Medicare is based on long-standing work that I have done protecting seniors from scams.
我关于保护社会保障和医疗保险的工作是基于我长期以来为保护老年人免受诈骗所做的工作。
My values have not changed.
我的价值观没有改变。
And what is important is that there is a president who actually brings values and a perspective that is about lifting people up and not beating people down and name-calling.
重要的是，有一位总统实际上带来了价值观和一种提升人民而不是贬低人民和辱骂他人的视角。
The true measure of the leader is the leader who actually understands the strength is not in beating people down, it's in lifting people up.
真正的领导者，是那些懂得力量不在于打压他人，而在于提升他人的人。
I intend to be that president.
我打算成为那样的总统。
President Trump, your response?
特朗普总统，您的回应？
Well, first of all, I wasn't given $400 million.
首先，我没有得到4亿美元。
I wish I was.
我倒希望有。
My father was a Brooklyn builder, Brooklyn Queens, and a great father, and I learned a lot from him.
我父亲是布鲁克林的建筑商，布鲁克林皇后区，他是个伟大的父亲，我从他那里学到了很多。
But I was given a fraction of that, a tiny fraction, and I built it into many, many billions of dollars, many, many billions.
但我得到的只是其中的一小部分，非常小的一部分，而我把它变成了数十亿，很多很多亿。
And when people see it, they are even surprised.
当人们看到这一点时，他们甚至感到惊讶。
So we don't have to talk about that.
所以我们不必谈论这个。
Fracking?
水力压裂？
She's been against it for 12 years.
她已经反对了12年。
Defund the police?
削减警察经费？
She's been against that forever.
她一直反对这个。
She gave all that stuff up.
她放弃了所有这些东西。
Very wrongly very horribly and everybody's laughing at it.
非常错误，非常糟糕，大家都对此嗤之以鼻。
Okay, they're all laughing at it She gave up at least 12 and probably 14 or 15 different policies like she was big on defund the police in Minnesota She went out.
好吧，他们都在嘲笑她。她至少放弃了12个，可能14或15个不同的政策，比如她在明尼苏达州大力支持削减警察经费，她出去了。
Wait a minute.
等一下。
I'm talking now If you don't mind, please Does that sound familiar?
我现在在说话，如果你不介意的话，这听起来熟悉吗？
She went out
她出去了
She went out in Minnesota and wanted to let criminals that killed people, that burned down Minneapolis, she went out and raised money to get them out of jail.
她在明尼苏达州出去，想要释放那些杀人犯，那些烧毁了明尼阿波利斯的人，她出去筹钱让他们出狱。
She did things that nobody would ever think of.
她做了一些没人会想到的事情。
Now she wants to do transgender operations on illegal aliens that are in prison.
现在她想给那些在监狱里的非法移民做变性手术。
This is a radical left liberal that would do this.
这是一个激进的左翼自由派会做的事情。
She wants to confiscate your guns, and she will never allow fracking in Pennsylvania.
她想没收你的枪，她永远不会允许在宾夕法尼亚州进行水力压裂。
If she won the election, fracking in Pennsylvania will end on day one.
如果她赢得选举，宾夕法尼亚州的水力压裂将在第一天结束。
Just to finish, one thing, so important in my opinion.
最后，我想说一件事，在我看来非常重要。
So I got the oil business going like nobody has ever done before.
所以我让石油生意做得比以往任何人都好。
They took, when they took over, they got rid of it, started getting rid of it, and the prices were going up the roof.
他们接手后，就开始废除，价格开始飙升。
They immediately let these guys go to where they were.
他们立即让这些人回到原来的位置。
I would have been five times, four times, five times higher, because you're talking about three and a half years ago.
我本可以高出四五倍，因为你在谈论三年半前的事情。
They got it up to where I was because they had no choice, because the prices of energy were quadrupling and doubling.
他们不得不这样做，因为能源价格在翻倍和四倍上涨。
You saw what happened to gasoline.
你看到了汽油发生了什么。
So they said, let's go back to Trump.
所以他们说，让我们回到特朗普时代。
But if she won the election the day after that election,
但如果她在那次选举后的第二天获胜，
They'll go back to destroying our country, and oil will be dead, fossil fuel will be dead.
他们将回到摧毁我们国家的状态，石油将死，化石燃料将死。
We'll go back to windmills, and we'll go back to solar, where they need a whole desert to get some energy to come out of.
我们将回到风车，回到太阳能，那里需要整个沙漠才能获得一些能量。
You ever see a solar plant?
你见过太阳能发电厂吗？
By the way, I'm a big fan of solar.
顺便说一下，我是太阳能的忠实粉丝。
But they take
但他们需要
400, 500 acres of desert soil.
400到500英亩的沙漠土地。
These are not good things for the environment, as she understands.
这对环境来说不是好事，正如她所理解的那样。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Lindsey, thank you.
林赛，谢谢。
We have an election in just 56 days.
我们还有56天就要选举了。
And I want to talk about the peaceful transfer of power, which of course we all know is a cornerstone of our democracy and the role of a president in a moment of crisis.
我想谈谈权力的和平过渡，这当然是我们民主的基石，以及总统在危机时刻的角色。
Mr. President, on January 6th, you told your supporters to march to the Capitol.
总统先生，1月6日，你告诉你的支持者们向国会大厦进发。
You said you would be right there with them.
你说你会和他们在一起。
The country and the world saw what played out at the Capitol that day, the officers coming under attack.
那天，国家和世界都看到了国会大厦发生的事情，警官们遭到攻击。
Aides in the West Wing say you watched it unfold on television off the Oval Office.
西翼的工作人员说，你在椭圆形办公室外通过电视观看了这一切。
You did send out tweets, but it was more than two hours before you sent out that video message telling your supporters to go home.
你确实发了推文，但你在两个多小时后才发出视频信息，告诉你的支持者们回家。
Is there anything you regret about what you did on that day?
你对那天所做的事情有什么后悔的吗？
You just said a thing that isn't covered.
你刚刚说了一件没有被报道的事情。
Peacefully and patriotically, I said during my speech, not later on.
在我的演讲中，我说的是和平地和爱国地，不是后来。
Peacefully and patriotically.
和平地和爱国地。
And nobody on the other side was killed.
而且对方没有人被杀。
Ashley Babbitt was shot by an out of control police officer that should have never
阿什利·巴比特被一个失控的警察开枪打死，他本不应该
ever shot her.
开枪打她的。
It's a disgrace.
这是耻辱。
But we didn't do this group of people that have been treated so badly.
但我们没有对这群被如此对待的人这样做。
I ask, what about all the people that are pouring into our country and killing people that she allowed to pour in?
我问，她允许涌入我们国家并杀害人民的人怎么办？
She was the borders are remember that she was the borders are she doesn't want to be called the borders are because she's embarrassed by the border.
她说边境问题，记得吗？她说边境问题，她不想被称为边境问题，因为她对边境感到尴尬。
In fact, she said at the beginning, Well, I'm surprised you're not talking about the border yet.
事实上，她一开始就说，我惊讶你还没谈到边境问题。
That's because she knows what a bad job they've done.
那是因为她知道他们做得有多糟糕。
What about those people?
那些人怎么办？
What are they gonna be prosecuted?
他们会受到起诉吗？
When are these people from countries all over the world, not just South America, they're coming in from all over the world, David, all over the world, and crime rates are down all over the world because of it.
这些来自世界各地的人，不仅仅是南美洲，他们来自世界各地，大卫，世界各地，犯罪率因此下降了。
But one of those, David, when are those people gonna be prosecuted?
但大卫，那些人什么时候会被起诉？
When are the people that burned down Minneapolis gonna be prosecuted?
那些烧毁明尼阿波利斯的人什么时候会被起诉？
Or in Seattle, they went into Seattle, they took over a big percentage of the city of Seattle.
或者在西雅图，他们进入了西雅图，占据了城市的大部分。
When are those people gonna be prosecuted?
那些人什么时候会被起诉？
But let me just ask you.
但让我问你。
You might ask her that question.
你可能会问她那个问题。
You were the president.
你是总统。
You were watching it unfold on television.
你在电视上看着这一切发生。
It's a very simple question as we move forward toward another election.
这是一个非常简单的问题，因为我们正走向另一场选举。
Is there anything you regret about what you did on that day?
对于那天你所做的事情，你有什么后悔的吗？
I had nothing to do with that other than they asked me to make a speech.
除了他们让我发表演讲，我与此无关。
I showed up for a speech.
我出现是为了演讲。
I said, I think it's going to be big.
我说，我认为这会很大。
I went to Nancy Pelosi and the mayor of Washington, D.C., and the mayor put it back in writing, as you know.
我去找了南希·佩洛西和华盛顿特区的市长，市长把它写了下来，你知道的。
I said, you know, this is going to be a very big rally or whatever you want to call it.
我说，你知道，这将是一个非常大的集会，或者你想怎么称呼它。
And again, it wasn't done by me.
再说一遍，这不是我做的。
It was done by others.
是别人做的。
I said, I'd like to give you 10,000 National Guard or soldiers.
我说，我想给你一万名国民警卫队或士兵。
They rejected me.
他们拒绝了我。
Nancy Pelosi rejected me.
南希·佩洛西拒绝了我。
It was just two weeks ago.
就在两周前。
Her daughter has a tape of her saying she is fully responsible for what happened.
她女儿有一盘录像带，说她对发生的事情负全责。
They want to get rid of that tape.
他们想销毁那盘录像带。
It would have never happened if Nancy Pelosi and the mayor of Washington did their jobs.
如果南希·佩洛西和华盛顿特区的市长做好他们的工作，这一切都不会发生。
I wasn't responsible for security.
我不负责安保。
Nancy Pelosi was responsible.
南希·佩洛西负责。
She didn't do her job.
她没有尽职。
The question was about you as president, not about former Speaker Pelosi.
问题是关于你作为总统的，不是关于前议长佩洛西的。
But I do want Vice President Harris to respond here.
但我确实希望副总统哈里斯在这里回应。
I was at the Capitol on January 6th.
我在1月6日的国会大厦。
I was the vice president-elect.
我是当选副总统。
I was also an acting senator.
我也是代理参议员。
I was there.
我在那里。
And on that day, the President of the United States incited a violent mob to attack our nation's Capitol, to desecrate our nation's Capitol.
那天，美国总统煽动了一群暴徒攻击我们的国会大厦，亵渎我们的国会大厦。
On that day, 140 law enforcement officers were injured, and some died.
那天，140名执法人员受伤，有些人牺牲了。
And understand, the former president has been indicted and impeached for exactly that reason.
而且，前总统因这个原因被起诉和弹劾。
But this is not an isolated situation.
但这不是一个孤立的事件。
Let's remember Charlottesville, where there was a mob of people carrying tiki torches, spewing anti-Semitic hate.
让我们记住夏洛茨维尔，那里有一群人拿着火把，散布反犹太仇恨。
And what did the president then at the time say?
当时的总统说了什么？
There were fine people on each side.
双方都有好人。
Let's remember.
让我们记住。
that when it came to the Proud Boys, a militia, the president said, the former president said, stand back and stand by.
当谈到骄傲男孩，一个民兵组织时，前总统说，退后待命。
So for everyone watching who remembers what January 6th was, I say we don't have to go back.
所以，对于所有记得1月6日的人，我说我们不必回去。
Let's not go back.
让我们不要回去。
We're not going back.
我们不会回去。
It's time to turn the page.
是时候翻开新的一页了。
And if that was a bridge too far for you, well, there is a place in our campaign for you to stand for country, to stand for our democracy, to stand for rule of law, and to end the chaos
如果那对你来说太遥远了，好吧，在我们的竞选中有一个地方让你为国家站出来，为我们的民主站出来，为法治站出来，结束混乱
and to end the approach that is about attacking the foundations of our democracy, because you don't like the outcome.
并结束那种因为不喜欢结果而攻击我们民主基础的做法。
And be clear on that point.
这一点要明确。
Donald Trump, the candidate, has said in this election there will be a bloodbath if this and the outcome of this election is not to his liking.
唐纳德·特朗普，这位候选人，在这次选举中说，如果结果不如他所愿，将会发生流血事件。
Let's turn the page on this.
让我们翻开这一页。
Let's not go back.
让我们不要回去。
Let's chart a course for the future and not go backwards to the past.
让我们为未来制定路线，而不是回到过去。
Let me just follow up here.
让我在这里补充一下。
It was a different term, and it was a term that related to energy, because they have destroyed our energy business.
这是一个不同的术语，它与能源有关，因为他们摧毁了我们的能源产业。
That was where Bloodbath was.
那就是“血腥屠杀”发生的地方。
Also, on Charlottesville, that story has been, as you would say, debunked.
还有，关于夏洛茨维尔的故事，正如你所说，已经被揭穿了。
Laura Ingram,
劳拉·英格拉姆，
Sean Hannity, Jesse, all of these people, they covered it.
肖恩·汉尼提，杰西，所有这些人，他们都报道了。
If they go an extra sentence, they will see it was perfect.
如果他们再多说一句话，他们就会看到这是完美的。
It was debunked in almost every newspaper, but they still bring it up, just like they bring 2025 up.
几乎每家报纸都揭穿了这个故事，但他们仍然提起它，就像他们提起2025年一样。
They bring all of this stuff up.
他们提起所有这些事情。
I ask you this, you talk about the Capitol.
我问你，你谈到国会山。
Why are we allowing these millions of people to come through on the southern border?
为什么我们允许这些数百万人通过南部边境进来？
How come she's not doing anything?
她为什么什么都不做？
And I'll tell you what I would do, and I would be very proud to do it.
我会告诉你我会怎么做，我会非常自豪地去做。
I would say we would both leave this debate right now.
我会说我们现在就结束这场辩论。
I'd like to see her go down
我想看她下去
to Washington D.C.
到华盛顿特区
during this debate, because we're wasting a lot of time, go down to, because she's been so bad, it's so ridiculous, go down to Washington D.C.
在这场辩论期间，因为我们浪费了很多时间，下去，因为她做得太糟糕了，太荒谬了，下去到华盛顿特区
and let her sign a bill to close up the border.
让她签署一项关闭边境的法案。
Because they have the right to do it.
因为他们有权这样做。
They don't need bills.
他们不需要法案。
They have the right to do it.
他们有权这样做。
The President of the United States, you'll get him out of bed, you'll wake him up at 4 o'clock in the afternoon, you'll say, come on, come on down to the office, let's sign a bill.
美国总统，你会把他从床上叫起来，下午4点叫醒他，你会说，快点，快点到办公室来，让我们签署一项法案。
If he signs a bill that the border is closed, all he has to do is say it to the border patrol, who are phenomenal.
如果他签署了一项关闭边境的法案，他只需要告诉边境巡逻队，他们是了不起的。
If they do that, the border is closed.
如果他们这样做，边境就关闭了。
Those people are killing many people, unlike J6.
那些人杀死了很多人，不像J6。
We talked immigration here tonight.
我们今晚在这里谈到了移民。
I do want to focus on this next issue to both of you, because it really brings us, this into focus, truth in these times that we're living in.
我想把重点放在下一个问题上，因为这确实让我们，在这个我们生活的时代，聚焦于真相。
Mr. President, for three and a half years after you lost the 2020 election, you repeatedly falsely claimed that you won, many times saying you won in a landslide.
总统先生，在你输掉2020年大选后的三年半里，你一再错误地声称你赢了，多次说你以压倒性优势获胜。
In the past couple of weeks leading up to this debate, you have said, quote, you lost by a whisker, that you, quote, didn't quite make it, that you came up a little bit short.
在过去的几周里，直到这场辩论之前，你说，引述，你输得很接近，你，引述，差一点就赢了，你差一点就赢了。
I said that?
我说过吗？
Are you now acknowledging that you lost in 2020?
你现在是否承认你在2020年输了？
No, I don't acknowledge that at all.
不，我根本不承认这一点。
But you did say that.
但你确实这么说了。
I said that sarcastically.
我是讽刺地说那句话的。
You know that.
你知道的。
We said, oh, we lost by a whisker.
我们说，哦，我们只差一点点。
That was said sarcastically.
那是讽刺的说法。
There's so much proof.
有太多证据了。
All you have to do is look at it.
你只需要看看就知道了。
And they should have sent it back to the legislatures for approval.
他们应该把它送回立法机构批准。
I got almost 75 million votes, the most votes any sitting president has ever gotten.
我获得了近7500万张选票，是任何在任总统中获得最多选票的。
I was told if I got 63, which was what I got in 2016, you can't be beaten.
有人告诉我，如果我得到6300万张选票，就像我在2016年那样，你就不会被打败。
The election people should never be thinking about an election is fraudulent.
选举人员永远不应该认为选举是欺诈的。
We need two things.
我们需要两样东西。
We need walls We need and we have to have it.
我们需要墙，我们必须要有。
We have to have borders and we have to have good elections Our elections are bad and a lot of these illegal immigrants coming in.
我们必须要有边界，我们必须要有好的选举。我们的选举很糟糕，很多非法移民正在涌入。
They're trying to get them to vote.
他们试图让他们投票。
They can't even speak English They don't even know what country they're in practically and these people are trying to get them to vote and that's why they're allowing Them to come into our country
他们甚至不会说英语，几乎不知道自己在哪个国家，这些人试图让他们投票，这就是为什么他们允许他们进入我们的国家。
You should watch all of these pieces of video.
你应该看看所有这些视频片段。
I didn't detect the sarcasm.
我没有察觉到讽刺。
Lost by a whisker.
只差一点点。
We didn't quite make it.
我们差点就成功了。
And we should just point out here, as clarification, and you know this, you and your allies, 60 cases in front of many judges, many of them Republican, and said there was no widespread fraud.
我们应该在这里澄清一下，你知道的，你和你的盟友，在许多法官面前有60个案件，其中许多是共和党法官，他们说没有广泛的欺诈行为。
No judge looked at it.
没有法官看过。
They said we didn't have standing.
他们说我们没有资格。
That's the other thing.
那是另一回事。
They said we didn't have standing, a technicality.
他们说我们没有资格，这是个技术问题。
Can you imagine a system where a person in an election doesn't have standing?
你能想象一个选举系统中，一个人没有资格吗？
The President of the United States doesn't have standing.
美国总统没有资格。
That's how we lost.
这就是我们失败的原因。
If you look at the facts, and I'd love to have you do a special on it,
如果你看看事实，我很乐意让你为此做一个特别报道，
I'll show you Georgia, and I'll show you Wisconsin, and I'll show you Pennsylvania, and I'll show you — we have so many facts and statistics.
我会给你看乔治亚州，我会给你看威斯康星州，我会给你看宾夕法尼亚州，我会给你看——我们有很多事实和数据。
But you know what?
但你知道吗？
That doesn't matter, because we have to solve the problem that we have right now.
这并不重要，因为我们必须解决我们现在面临的问题。
That's old news.
那是旧闻了。
And the problem that we have right now is we have a nation in decline, and they have put it into decline.
我们现在面临的问题是，我们的国家正在衰退，他们让它衰退了。
We have a nation that is dying, David.
我们的国家正在衰亡，大卫。
Mr. President, thank you.
总统先生，谢谢你。
Vice President Harris, you heard the president there tonight.
哈里斯副总统，你今晚听到了总统的话。
He said he didn't say that, that he lost by a whisker.
他说他没说过，他说他只差一点点。
So he still believes he did not lose the election that was won by President Biden and yourself.
所以他仍然认为他没有输掉那场由拜登总统和你赢得的选举。
But I do want to ask you about something that's come up in the last couple of days.
但我确实想问你一些最近几天出现的事情。
This was a post from President Trump.
这是特朗普总统的一篇帖子。
about this upcoming election just weeks away.
关于即将到来的选举，就在几周后。
He said, when I win, those people who cheated, and then he lists donors, voters, election officials, he says, will be prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law, which will include long-term prison sentences.
他说，当我赢了，那些作弊的人，然后他列出了捐赠者、选民、选举官员，他说，将会受到法律最严厉的惩罚，包括长期监禁。
One of your campaign's top lawyers responded, saying, we won't let Donald Trump intimidate us.
你的竞选团队的一位顶级律师回应说，我们不会让唐纳德·特朗普吓倒我们。
We won't let him suppress the vote.
我们不会让他压制选票。
Is that what you believe he's trying to do here?
你认为他在这里试图这样做吗？
Donald Trump was fired by 81 million people.
唐纳德·特朗普被8100万人解雇了。
So let's be clear about that.
所以让我们明确这一点。
And clearly he is having a very difficult time processing that.
显然他正在非常艰难地接受这一点。
But we cannot afford to have a President of the United States who attempts, as he did in the past, to upend the will of the voters in a free and fair election.
但我们不能负担得起一个试图像他过去那样颠覆自由公正选举中选民意愿的美国总统。
And I'm going to tell you that I have traveled the world as Vice President of the United States, and world leaders are laughing at Donald Trump.
我要告诉你，作为美国副总统，我走遍了世界，世界领导人都在嘲笑唐纳德·特朗普。
I have talked with military leaders, some of whom worked with you, and they say you're a disgrace.
我和一些与你共事过的军事领导人谈过，他们说你是个耻辱。
And when you then talk in this way in a presidential debate and deny what over and over again are court cases you have lost because you did in fact lose that election, it leads one to believe that perhaps we do not have in the candidate to my right the temperament
当你在总统辩论中这样说话，并一再否认那些你已经输掉的法庭案件，因为你确实输掉了那场选举，这让人怀疑我们右边的候选人是否具备
or the ability to not be confused about fact.
或者是否有能力不被事实所迷惑。
That's deeply troubling, and the American people deserve better.
这非常令人担忧，美国人民值得更好。
I'll give you one minute to respond, Mr. President.
总统先生，我给你一分钟回应。
Let me just tell you about world leaders.
让我告诉你一些关于世界领导人的事。
Viktor Orban, one of the most respected men.
维克托·欧尔班，是最受尊敬的人之一。
They call him a strong man.
他们称他为强人。
He's a tough person.
他是个强硬的人。
Smart.
聪明。
Prime Minister of Hungary.
匈牙利总理。
They said, why is the whole world blowing up?
他们问，为什么整个世界都在动荡？
Three years ago, it wasn't.
三年前，并没有这样。
Why is it blowing up?
为什么现在动荡不安？
He said, because you need Trump back as president.
他说，因为我们需要特朗普重新当总统。
They were afraid of him.
他们害怕他。
China was afraid.
中国也害怕。
And I don't like to use the word afraid, but I'm just quoting him.
我不喜欢用“害怕”这个词，但我只是在引用他的话。
China was afraid of him.
中国害怕他。
North Korea was afraid of him.
朝鲜也害怕他。
Look at what's going on with North Korea, by the way.
顺便看看朝鲜现在的情况。
He said Russia was afraid of him.
他说俄罗斯也害怕他。
I ended the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and Biden put it back on day one, but he ended the XL pipeline.
我终止了北溪2号管道，拜登上任第一天就恢复了，但他终止了XL管道。
The XL pipeline in our country, he ended that, but he let the Russians build a pipeline going all over Europe and heading into Germany, the biggest pipeline in the world.
我们国家的XL管道，他终止了，却让俄罗斯在欧洲各地修建管道，通往德国，这是世界上最大的管道。
Look.
看。
Victor Orban said it.
欧尔班说的。
He said the most respected, most feared person is Donald Trump.
他说最受尊敬、最令人畏惧的人是唐纳德·特朗普。
We had no problems when Trump was president.
特朗普当总统时，我们没有问题。
But when this weak, pathetic man that you saw at a debate just a few months ago, that if he weren't in that debate, he'd be running instead of her.
但当这个软弱无能的人，几个月前在辩论中出现，如果不是他，她就不会参加辩论。
She got no votes.
她没有得到选票。
He got 14 million votes.
他得到了1400万张选票。
What you did, you talk about a threat to democracy.
你所说的，是对民主的威胁。
He got 14 million votes and they threw him out of office.
他得到了1400万张选票，却被赶出了办公室。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
I'll give you a little secret.
我给你一个小秘密。
He hates her.
他恨她。
He can't stand her.
他无法忍受她。
But he got 14 million votes.
但他得到了1400万张选票。
They threw him out.
他们把他赶出去了。
She got zero votes.
她一票都没得到。
And when she ran, she was the first one to leave because she failed.
她竞选时，第一个退出的就是她，因为她失败了。
And now she's running.
现在她又来竞选了。
I don't understand it, but I'm okay with it because...
我不明白，但我无所谓，因为...
Your time is up.
你的时间到了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I think we're going to do very well.
我认为我们会做得很好。
We've got a lot more to get to.
我们还有很多要讨论的。
Turning now to the Israel-Hamas war and the hostages who are still being held, Americans among them.
现在转向以色列-哈马斯战争和仍被扣押的人质，其中包括美国人。
Vice President Harris, in December you said, quote, Israel has a right to defend itself.
哈里斯副总统，去年12月你曾说，引述，以色列有权自卫。
But you added, quote, it matters how, saying international humanitarian law must be respected.
但你补充说，引述，重要的是如何自卫，国际人道法必须得到尊重。
Israel must do more to protect innocent civilians.
以色列必须做更多来保护无辜平民。
You said that nine months ago.
你九个月前这么说过。
Now an estimated 40,000 Palestinians are dead.
现在估计有4万名巴勒斯坦人死亡。
Nearly 100 hostages remain.
近百名人质仍被扣押。
Just last week, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said there's not a deal in the making.
就在上周，本雅明·内塔尼亚胡总理表示，目前没有达成协议。
President Biden has not been able to break through the stalemate.
拜登总统未能打破僵局。
How would you do it?
你会怎么做？
Well, let's understand how we got here.
好吧，让我们先了解我们是如何走到这一步的。
On October 7, Hamas, a terrorist organization,
10月7日，哈马斯，一个恐怖组织，
slaughtered 1,200 Israelis, many of them young people who were simply attending a concert.
屠杀了1200名以色列人，其中许多是年轻人，他们只是在参加一场音乐会。
Women were horribly raped.
妇女遭到可怕的强奸。
And so absolutely, I said then, I say now, Israel has a right to defend itself.
所以绝对没错，我当时说，我现在也说，以色列有权自卫。
We would.
我们也会。
And how it does so matters, because it is also true far too many innocent Palestinians have been killed.
但如何自卫很重要，因为确实有太多无辜的巴勒斯坦人被杀。
Children, mothers.
孩子，母亲。
What we know is that this war must end.
我们知道的是，这场战争必须结束。
It must end immediately, and the way it will end is we need a ceasefire deal and we need the hostages out.
必须立即结束，结束的方式是我们需要停火协议，我们需要人质获释。
And so we will continue to work around the clock on that.
因此，我们将继续昼夜不停地为此努力。
Work around the clock also understanding that we must chart a course for a two-state solution.
我们也必须日夜不停地工作，理解我们必须为两国解决方案制定路线。
And in that solution, there must be security for the Israeli people and Israel and an equal measure for the Palestinians.
在这个解决方案中，必须确保以色列人民和以色列的安全，同时也要为巴勒斯坦人提供同等的安全保障。
But the one thing I will assure you always, I will always give Israel the ability to defend itself, in particular as it relates to Iran and any threat that Iran and its proxies pose to Israel.
但我可以向你们保证，我将始终给予以色列自卫的能力，特别是当涉及到伊朗及其代理人对以色列构成的任何威胁时。
But we must have a two-state solution where we can rebuild Gaza, where the Palestinians have security, self-determination, and the dignity they so rightly deserve.
但我们必须有一个两国解决方案，在那里我们可以重建加沙，让巴勒斯坦人拥有安全、自决和应有的尊严。
President Trump, how would you negotiate with Netanyahu and also Hamas in order to get the hostages out and prevent the killing of more innocent civilians in Gaza?
特朗普总统，您将如何与内塔尼亚胡和哈马斯谈判，以解救人质并防止加沙更多无辜平民被杀害？
If I were president, it would have never started.
如果我是总统，这一切都不会发生。
If I were president, Russia would have never, ever, I know Putin very well, he would have never, and there was no threat of it either, by the way, for four years, have gone into Ukraine and killed millions of people when you add it up.
如果我是总统，俄罗斯绝不会，我非常了解普京，他绝不会，而且顺便说一句，在四年里，绝不会入侵乌克兰并导致数百万人死亡。
Far worse than people understand what's going on over there.
那里的情况远比人们理解的更糟糕。
But when she mentions about Israel, all of a sudden, she hates Israel.
但当她提到以色列时，她突然就讨厌以色列了。
She wouldn't even meet with Netanyahu when he went to Congress to make a very important speech.
当内塔尼亚胡去国会发表重要演讲时，她甚至拒绝会见他。
She refused to be there because she was at a sorority party of hers.
她拒绝出席是因为她在参加一个姐妹会的派对。
She wanted to go to the sorority party.
她想去参加那个姐妹会的派对。
She hates Israel.
她讨厌以色列。
If she's president, I believe that Israel will not exist within two years from now.
如果她成为总统，我相信以色列将在两年内不复存在。
And I've been pretty good at predictions, and I hope I'm wrong about that one.
我的预测一直很准，我希望这次是错的。
She hates Israel.
她讨厌以色列。
At the same time, in her own way, she hates the Arab population, because the whole place is going to get blown up.
同时，以她自己的方式，她也讨厌阿拉伯人口，因为整个地区都将被摧毁。
Arabs, Jewish people, Israel.
阿拉伯人，犹太人，以色列。
Israel will be gone.
以色列将不复存在。
It would have never happened.
这一切都不会发生。
Iran was broke under Donald Trump.
伊朗在唐纳德·特朗普的领导下破产了。
Now Iran has $300 billion because they took off all the sanctions that I had.
现在伊朗有3000亿美元，因为他们取消了所有我施加的制裁。
Iran had no money for Hamas or Hezbollah or any of the 28 different spheres of terror.
伊朗没有钱给哈马斯或真主党或任何28个恐怖组织。
And they are spheres of terror, horrible terror.
他们是恐怖组织，可怕的恐怖组织。
They had no money.
他们没有钱。
It was a big story, and you know it.
这是一个大新闻，你知道的。
You covered it very well, actually.
你报道得很好，实际上。
They had no money for terror.
他们没有钱用于恐怖活动。
They were broke.
他们破产了。
Now they're a rich nation.
现在他们是一个富裕的国家。
And now what they're doing is they're spreading that money around.
他们现在做的就是把钱到处撒。
Look at what's happening with the Houthis and Yemen.
看看胡塞武装和也门的情况。
Look at what's going on in the Middle East.
看看中东正在发生什么。
This would have never happened.
这根本不会发生。
I will get that settled and fast, and I'll get the war with Ukraine and Russia ended.
我会迅速解决这个问题，我会结束乌克兰和俄罗斯的战争。
If I'm president-elect, I'll get it done before even becoming president.
如果我当选总统，我会在就任前就完成这件事。
Vice President Harris, he says you hate Israel.
哈里斯副总统，他说你讨厌以色列。
That's absolutely not true.
这绝对不是真的。
I have my entire career and life supported Israel and the Israeli people.
我整个职业生涯和一生都支持以色列和以色列人民。
He knows that.
他知道这一点。
He's trying to again divide and distract
他试图再次分裂和转移注意力
from the reality, which is it is very well known that Donald Trump is weak and wrong on national security and foreign policy.
从现实来看，众所周知，唐纳德·特朗普在国家安全和外交政策上软弱且错误。
It is well known that he admires dictators, wants to be a dictator on day one according to himself.
众所周知，他崇拜独裁者，根据他自己所说，他想在第一天就成为独裁者。
It is well known that he said of Putin that he can do whatever the hell he wants and go into Ukraine.
众所周知，他曾说普京可以为所欲为，进入乌克兰。
It is well known that he said when Russia went into Ukraine, it was brilliant.
众所周知，当俄罗斯进入乌克兰时，他说这是天才之举。
It is well known he exchanged love letters with Kim Jong-un.
众所周知，他与金正恩互通信件，表达爱意。
And it is absolutely well known that these dictators and autocrats are rooting for you to be president again, because they're so clear they can manipulate you with flattery and favors.
而且绝对众所周知，这些独裁者和专制者都希望你再次当选总统，因为他们很清楚可以用奉承和恩惠来操纵你。
And that is why
这就是为什么
So many military leaders who you have worked with have told me you are a disgrace.
许多与你共事的军事领导人告诉我，你是个耻辱。
That is why we understand that we have to have a president who is not consistently weak and wrong on national security, including the importance of upholding and respecting in highest regard our military.
这就是为什么我们明白，我们需要一个在国家安全问题上不总是软弱和错误的总统，包括高度重视和支持我们的军队。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢你。
And she's the one that caused it.
而她才是造成这一切的人。
That's weak on national security by allowing every nation last month for the year 168 different countries sending people into our country.
上个月，允许168个不同国家的人进入我国，这是对国家安全的软弱。
Their crime weights are way down.
他们的犯罪率大幅下降。
Putin endorsed her last week said I hope she wins and I think he meant it.
普京上周支持她，说希望她赢，我想他是认真的。
because what he's gotten away with is absolutely incredible.
因为他所逃避的惩罚是绝对难以置信的。
It wouldn't have happened with me.
如果是我的话，这种情况不会发生。
The leaders of other countries think that they're weak and incompetent, and they are.
其他国家的领导人认为他们软弱无能，他们确实如此。
They're grossly incompetent.
他们极其无能。
And I just ask one question.
我只想问一个问题。
Why does Biden go in and kill the Keystone pipeline and approve the single biggest deal that Russia's ever made, Nord Stream 2, the biggest pipeline anywhere in the world going to Germany and all over Europe?
为什么拜登要关闭基石管道，并批准俄罗斯有史以来最大的交易——北溪2号，这是世界上最大的管道，通往德国和整个欧洲？
because they're weak and they're ineffective.
因为他们软弱无能。
And Biden, by the way, gets paid a lot of money.
顺便说一下，拜登赚了很多钱。
Thank you.
谢谢。
We have a lot of issues to get to.
我们有很多问题要讨论。
We'll be right back with much more of this historic ABC News presidential debate from the National Constitution Center right here in Philadelphia.
我们马上回来，继续这场在费城国家宪法中心举行的历史性ABC新闻总统辩论。
Back in a moment.
稍后回来。
The ABC News presidential debate will continue after this.
ABC新闻总统辩论将继续进行。
from the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania.
来自宾夕法尼亚州费城的国家宪法中心。
Here again, David Muir and Lindsay Davis.
再次由大卫·缪尔和林赛·戴维斯主持。
Welcome back to this historic ABC News presidential debate tonight.
欢迎回到今晚这场历史性的ABC新闻总统辩论。
We're going to continue here, and I want to turn to the war in Ukraine.
我们将继续讨论，我想转向乌克兰战争。
We're now two and a half years into this conflict.
现在这场冲突已经持续了两年半。
Mr. President, it has been the position of the Biden administration that we must defend Ukraine from Russia, from Vladimir Putin, to defend their sovereignty, their democracy, that it's in America's best interest to do so, arguing that if Putin wins,
总统先生，拜登政府的立场是我们必须保卫乌克兰免受俄罗斯、弗拉基米尔·普京的侵害，以保卫他们的主权和民主，认为这样做符合美国的最佳利益，并辩称如果普京获胜，
He may be emboldened to move even further into other countries.
他可能会更加大胆地进一步入侵其他国家。
You have said you would solve this war in 24 hours.
你曾说过你会在24小时内解决这场战争。
You said so just before the break tonight.
你今晚休息前就是这么说的。
How exactly would you do that?
你具体会怎么做？
And I want to ask you a very simple question tonight.
今晚我想问你一个非常简单的问题。
Do you want Ukraine to win this war?
你希望乌克兰赢得这场战争吗？
I want the war to stop.
我希望战争停止。
I want to save lives that are being uselessly people being killed by the millions.
我希望拯救那些无谓牺牲的生命，数百万人正在被杀害。
It's the millions.
是数百万人。
It's so much worse than the numbers that you're getting, which are fake numbers.
情况比你们得到的假数字要糟糕得多。
Look,
看，
We're in for 250 billion or more because they don't ask Europe, which is a much bigger beneficiary to getting this thing done than we are.
我们为此花费了2500亿或更多，因为他们没有像我那样要求欧洲，欧洲是比我们更大的受益者。
They're in for 150 billion dollars less because Biden and you don't have the courage to ask Europe like I did with NATO.
他们少花了1500亿美元，因为拜登和你没有勇气像我对北约那样要求欧洲。
They paid billions and billions, hundreds of billions of dollars when I said
他们支付了数十亿、数百亿美元，当我告诉他们
Either you pay up, or we're not going to protect you anymore.
要么你们付钱，要么我们不再保护你们。
So that's maybe one of the reasons they don't like me as much as they like weak people.
所以这可能是他们不喜欢我，而更喜欢软弱的人的原因之一。
But you take a look at what's happening.
但你们看看现在的情况。
We're in for $250 to $275 billion.
我们要付出2500亿到2750亿美元。
They're into $100 to $150.
他们只花了1000亿到1500亿。
They should be forced to equalize.
他们应该被强制平等。
With that being said, I want to get the war settled.
话虽如此，我想结束这场战争。
I know Zelensky very well, and I know Putin very well.
我非常了解泽连斯基，也非常了解普京。
I have a good relationship, and they respect
我和他们关系很好，他们尊重
your president, okay?
你们的总统，好吗？
They respect me.
他们尊重我。
They don't respect Biden.
他们不尊重拜登。
How would you respect him?
你怎么会尊重他？
Why?
For what reason?
出于什么原因？
He hasn't even made a phone call in two years to Putin, hasn't spoken to anybody.
他两年内甚至没有给普京打过电话，也没有和任何人谈过。
They don't even try and get it.
他们甚至不尝试去解决。
That is a war that's dying to be settled.
这是一场迫切需要解决的战争。
I will get it settled before I even become president.
我会在成为总统之前就解决它。
If I win, when I'm president-elect, and what I'll do is I'll speak to one, I'll speak to the other, I'll get them together.
如果我赢了，当我当选总统时，我会和一方谈，和另一方谈，我会让他们坐下来。
That war would have never happened.
那场战争根本不会发生。
And in fact, when I saw Putin after I left,
事实上，当我离开后见到普京，
Unfortunately, left because our country has gone to hell.
不幸的是，我离开了，因为我们的国家已经陷入困境。
But after I left, when I saw him building up soldiers, he did it after I left.
但当我离开后，看到他在集结士兵，他是在我离开后这么做的。
I said, oh, he must be negotiating.
我说，哦，他一定在谈判。
It must be a good, strong point of negotiation.
这一定是一个强有力的谈判点。
Well, it wasn't because Biden had no idea how to talk to him.
其实不是，因为拜登根本不知道怎么和他谈。
He had no idea how to stop it.
他根本不知道怎么阻止。
And now you have millions of people dead and it's only getting worse.
现在已经有数百万人死亡，情况只会越来越糟。
And it could lead to World War Three.
这可能导致第三次世界大战。
Don't kid yourself, David.
别自欺欺人，大卫。
We're playing with World War III, and we have a president that we don't even know if he's—where is our president?
我们正在玩火，而我们甚至不知道我们的总统在哪里。
We don't even know if he's a president.
我们甚至不知道他是不是总统。
And just to clarify here— They threw him out of a campaign like a dog.
澄清一下——他们像赶狗一样把他赶出了竞选。
We don't even know.
我们甚至不知道。
Is he our president?
他还是我们的总统吗？
But we have a president— Mr. President— —that doesn't know he's alive.
但我们有一位总统——总统先生——他都不知道自己还活着。
Your time is up.
你的时间到了。
Just to clarify the question.
澄清一下问题。
Do you believe it's in the U.S.
你认为乌克兰赢得这场战争是否符合美国的最佳利益，是还是不是？
best interest for Ukraine to win this war, yes or no?
我认为美国的最佳利益是结束这场战争，尽快解决。
I think it's the U.S.
谈判达成协议。
best interest to get this war finished and just get it done.
因为我们必须阻止这些生命的毁灭。
Negotiate a deal.
我想把这个话题交给副总统哈里斯。
Because we have to stop all of these human lives from being destroyed.
我想听听你对乌克兰支持的看法。
I want to take this to Vice President Harris.
但作为总司令，如果你当选，你会如何处理普京？
I want to get your thoughts on support for Ukraine in this moment.
这会与拜登总统的做法有所不同吗？
But also, as Commander-in-Chief, if elected, how would you deal with Vladimir Putin?
首先，重要的是提醒前总统，你不是在和乔·拜登竞选，而是在和我竞选。
And would it be any different from what we're seeing from President Biden?
我认为唐纳德·特朗普说这场战争会在24小时内结束，是因为他会放弃。
Well, first of all, it's important to remind the former president you're not running against Joe Biden, you're running against me.
这不是我们作为美国人的立场。
I believe the reason that Donald Trump says that this war would be over within 24 hours is because he would just give it up.
让我们理解这里发生了什么。
And that's not who we are as Americans.
在俄罗斯入侵前几天，我实际上会见了泽连斯基，试图通过武力改变领土边界，违背最重要的国际规则和规范之一，即主权和领土完整的重要性。
Let's understand what happened here.
我会见了泽连斯基总统。
I actually met with Zelensky a few days before Russia invaded, tried through force to change territorial boundaries, to defy one of the most important international rules and norms, which is the importance of sovereignty and territorial integrity.
我与他分享了美国情报，告诉他如何自卫。
And I met with President Zelensky.
几天后，我去了北约的东部前线，去了波兰和罗马尼亚。
I shared with him American intelligence about how he could defend himself.
通过我和其他人的工作，我们聚集了50个国家支持乌克兰的正义防御。
Days later, I went to NATO's eastern flank, to Poland and Romania.
正因为我们的支持，因为我们的防空、弹药、火炮、标枪导弹和艾布拉姆斯坦克，乌克兰作为一个独立自由的国家屹立不倒。
And through the work that I and others did, we brought 50 countries together to support Ukraine in its righteous defense.
如果唐纳德·特朗普是总统，普京现在可能已经坐在基辅了。
And because of our support, because of the air defense, the ammunition, the artillery, the Javelins, the Abrams tanks that we have provided, Ukraine stands as an independent and free country.
理解这意味着什么，因为普京的议程不仅仅是关于乌克兰。
If Donald Trump were president, Putin would be sitting in Kiev right now.
理解为什么欧洲盟友和我们的北约盟友如此感激你不再是总统，我们理解世界上最伟大的军事联盟——北约的重要性。
And understand what that would mean, because Putin's agenda is not just about Ukraine.
如果唐纳德·特朗普是总统，普京现在可能已经坐在基辅了。
Understand why the European allies and our NATO allies are so thankful that you are no longer president, and that we understand the importance of the greatest military alliance the world has ever known, which is NATO.
理解这意味着什么，因为普京的议程不仅仅是关于乌克兰。
and what we have done to preserve the ability of Zelensky and the Ukrainians to fight for their independence.
我们为泽连斯基和乌克兰人保卫独立所做的努力。
Otherwise, Putin would be sitting in Kiev with his eyes on the rest of Europe, starting with Poland.
否则，普京就会坐在基辅，目光投向欧洲其他地区，首先是波兰。
And why don't you tell the 800,000 Polish-Americans right here in Pennsylvania how quickly you would give up for the sake of favor and what you think is a friendship with what is known to be a dictator who would eat you for lunch.
你为什么不告诉宾夕法尼亚州这里的80万波兰裔美国人，你会为了讨好和所谓的友谊而多么迅速地放弃，而对方是一个众所周知的独裁者，他会在午餐时把你吃掉。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢你。
We've heard from both of you on Ukraine tonight.
今晚我们已经听到了你们双方关于乌克兰的看法。
Afghanistan came up in the last hour.
阿富汗问题在上一个小时被提到了。
I wanted her to respond to something you said earlier.
我想让她回应你之前说的话。
Please, I'll give you a minute here.
请，我给你一分钟时间。
Putin would be sitting in Moscow, and he wouldn't have lost 300,000 men and women, but he would have been sitting in Moscow.
普京会坐在莫斯科，他不会损失30万男女，但他会坐在莫斯科。
Quiet, please.
请安静。
He would have been sitting in Moscow much happier than he is right now.
他会比现在更快乐地坐在莫斯科。
But eventually, you know, he's got a thing that other people don't have.
但最终，你知道，他有一些别人没有的东西。
He's got nuclear weapons.
他有核武器。
They don't ever talk about that.
他们从不谈论这个。
He's got nuclear weapons.
他有核武器。
Nobody ever thinks about that.
没人想过这个。
And eventually, maybe he'll use them, and maybe he hasn't been that threatening.
最终，也许他会使用它们，也许他并没有那么威胁。
But he does have that, something we don't even like to talk about.
但他确实有这个，我们甚至不喜欢谈论的东西。
Nobody likes to talk about it.
没人喜欢谈论它。
But just so you understand, they sent her to negotiate peace before this war started.
但为了让你明白，他们在战争开始前派她去谈判和平。
Three days later, he went in and he started the war because everything they said was weak and stupid.
三天后，他进去了，他开始了战争，因为他们的所有言论都是软弱和愚蠢的。
They said the wrong things.
他们说错了话。
That war should have never started.
那场战争本不应该开始。
She was the emissary.
她是特使。
They sent her in to negotiate with Zelensky and Putin.
他们派她去与泽连斯基和普京谈判。
And she did.
她去了。
And the war started three days later.
战争在三天后开始了。
And that's the kind of talent we have with her.
这就是我们与她拥有的那种人才。
She's worse than Biden, in my opinion.
在我看来，她比拜登更糟糕。
I think he's the worst president in the history of our country.
我认为他是我们国家历史上最糟糕的总统。
She goes down as the worst vice president in the history of our country.
她将成为我国历史上最糟糕的副总统。
But let me tell you something.
但让我告诉你一件事。
She is a horrible negotiator.
她是个糟糕的谈判者。
They sent her in to negotiate.
他们派她去谈判。
As soon as they left, Putin did the invasion.
他们一离开，普京就发动了入侵。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢你。
You did bring up something.
你确实提到了一些事情。
You said she went to negotiate with Vladimir Putin.
你说她去和弗拉基米尔·普京谈判。
Vice President Harris, have you ever met Vladimir Putin?
哈里斯副总统，你见过弗拉基米尔·普京吗？
Can you clarify tonight?
今晚你能澄清一下吗？
Yet again, I said at the beginning of this debate, you're going to hear a bunch of lies coming from this fellow.
再次，我在辩论开始时说过，你会听到这家伙说一堆谎言。
And that is another one.
那又是一个谎言。
When I went to meet with President Zelensky, I've now met with him over five times.
当我去见泽连斯基总统时，我现在已经见过他五次了。
The reality is it has been about standing as America always should, as a leader upholding international rules and norms, as a leader who shows strength, understanding that the alliances we have around the world are dependent on our ability to look out for our friends and not favor
现实是，美国一直应该站在领导地位，维护国际规则和规范，作为展现力量的领导者，理解我们在世界各地的联盟取决于我们照顾朋友的能力，而不是偏袒敌人，因为你崇拜强人而不是关心民主。
our enemies because you adore strongmen instead of caring about democracy.
而这正是这里的关键所在。
And that is very much what is at stake here.
美国总统是总司令，美国人民有权依赖
The president of the United States is commander in chief, and the American people have a right to rely
一位理解美国角色和责任重要性的总统，以确保稳定，并确保我们捍卫我们的原则，而不是为了个人奉承而牺牲它们。
on a president who understands the significance of America's role and responsibility in terms of ensuring that there is stability and ensuring we stand up for our principles and not sell them for the benefit of personal flattery.
我们已经谈到了乌克兰和弗拉基米尔·普京。
We've talked about Ukraine and Vladimir Putin.
我确实想谈谈阿富汗。
I do want to talk about Afghanistan.
这在辩论的第一小时就提到了。
It came up in the first hour of this debate.
我想转到阿富汗。
I want to move on to Afghanistan.
特朗普做了我见过的最了不起的事情。
Trump did the most amazing thing I've ever seen.
他让这些国家，当时是28个国家，都付了钱。
He got these countries, the 28 countries at the time, to pay up.
他说，我从未见过。
He said, I've never seen.
他是北约的负责人。
He's the head of NATO.
他说，我从未见过。
He said, I've never seen.
多年来，我们几乎支付了北约的全部费用。
For years, we were paying almost all of NATO.
我们被欧洲国家在贸易和北约上剥削了。
We were being ripped off by European nations, both on trade and on NATO.
我让他们付钱，说了一句你之前说过的话，如果你不付钱，我们不会保护你。
I got them to pay up by saying one of the statements you made before, if you don't pay, we're not going to protect you.
Otherwise, we would have never gotten it.
否则，我们永远也得不到它。
He said it was one of the most incredible jobs that he's ever seen done.
他说这是他见过的最不可思议的工作之一。
Thank you.
谢谢。
I want to turn to Afghanistan.
我想转向阿富汗问题。
It came up in the first hour of the debate, and we witnessed a poignant moment today on Capitol Hill honoring the soldiers who died in the chaotic withdrawal from Afghanistan.
这个问题在辩论的第一小时就被提出来了，今天我们在国会山见证了一个感人的时刻，纪念在阿富汗混乱撤军中牺牲的士兵。
I do want to ask the vice president, do you believe you bear any responsibility in the way that withdrawal played out?
我想问副总统，您是否认为您对撤军的方式负有任何责任？
Well, I will tell you, I agreed with President Biden's decision to pull out of Afghanistan.
好吧，我会告诉你，我同意拜登总统从阿富汗撤军的决定。
Four presidents said they would, and Joe Biden did.
四位总统都说过会这样做，而乔·拜登做到了。
And as a result, America's taxpayers are not paying the $300 million a day we were paying for that endless war.
结果，美国的纳税人不再为那场无休止的战争每天支付3亿美元。
And as of today, there is not one member of the United States military who is in active duty in a combat zone in any war zone around the world the first time this century.
截至今天，世界上没有任何一个战区的任何一名美国军人处于战斗状态，这是本世纪的第一次。
But let's understand how we got to where we are.
但让我们了解一下我们是如何走到这一步的。
Donald Trump, when he was president, negotiated one of the weakest deals you can imagine.
唐纳德·特朗普，当他担任总统时，谈判了一项你无法想象的弱协议。
He calls himself a dealmaker.
他自称是谈判高手。
Even his national security adviser said it was a weak, terrible deal.
甚至他的国家安全顾问也说这是一项软弱、糟糕的协议。
And here's how it went down.
事情是这样的。
He bypassed the Afghan government.
他绕过了阿富汗政府。
He negotiated directly with a terrorist organization called the Taliban.
他直接与一个名为塔利班的恐怖组织谈判。
The negotiation involved the Taliban getting 5,000 terrorists, Taliban terrorists, released.
谈判涉及塔利班释放5000名恐怖分子，塔利班恐怖分子。
And get this, no get this, and the president at the time invited the Taliban to Camp David.
而且，请注意，当时的总统邀请塔利班到戴维营。
a place of storied significance for us as Americans, a place where we honor the importance of American diplomacy, where we invite and receive respected world leaders, and this
对我们美国人来说，这是一个具有历史意义的地方，一个我们尊重美国外交重要性的地方，一个我们邀请和接待受尊敬的世界领袖的地方，而这个
former President, as President, invited them to Camp David because he does not, again, appreciate the role and responsibility of the President of the United States to be Commander-in-Chief with a level of respect.
前总统，作为总统，邀请他们到戴维营，因为他不，再次，不理解美国总统作为总司令的角色和责任，以及应有的尊重。
And this gets back to the point of how he has consistently disparaged and demeaned members of our military, fallen soldiers, and the work that we must do to uphold the strength
这又回到了他一贯贬低和贬低我们军队的成员、阵亡士兵以及我们必须做的工作，以维护
and the respect of the United States of America around the world.
和尊重美国在世界上的力量。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
副总统哈里斯，谢谢。
President Trump, your response to her saying that you began the negotiations with the Taliban?
特朗普总统，您对她所说的您开始与塔利班谈判的回应是什么？
If you take a look at that period of time, the Taliban was killing our soldiers, a lot of them, with snipers.
如果你看看那段时间，塔利班正在用狙击手杀死我们的士兵，很多。
And I got involved with the Taliban because the Taliban was doing the killing.
我与塔利班接触是因为塔利班在杀人。
That's the fighting force within Afghanistan.
那是阿富汗内部的战斗力量。
They don't bother doing that because, you know, they deal with the wrong people all the time.
他们不这样做是因为，你知道，他们总是和错误的人打交道。
But I got involved.
但我参与了。
And Abdul is the head of the Taliban.
阿卜杜勒是塔利班的首领。
He is still the head of the Taliban.
他仍然是塔利班的首领。
And I told Abdul, don't do it anymore.
我告诉阿卜杜勒，别再这么做了。
You do it anymore, you're going to have problems.
你再这么做，就会遇到麻烦。
And he said, why do you send me a picture of my house?
他问，你为什么给我发我家房子的照片？
I said, you're going to have to figure that out, Abdul.
我说，阿卜杜勒，你得自己想明白。
And for 18 months, we had nobody killed.
在18个月里，我们没有人被杀。
We did have an agreement negotiated by Mike Pompeo.
我们确实有一个由迈克·蓬佩奥谈判达成的协议。
It was a very good agreement.
那是一个非常好的协议。
The reason it was good, it was we were getting out.
它之所以好，是因为我们要撤离了。
We would have been out faster than them, but we wouldn't have lost the soldiers.
我们会比他们撤得更快，但我们不会损失士兵。
We wouldn't have left many Americans behind.
我们不会留下许多美国人。
We wouldn't have left.
我们不会留下。
$85 billion worth of brand-new beautiful military equipment behind and just to finish they Blew it the agreement said you have to do this this this this this and they didn't do it They didn't do it the agreement was
价值850亿美元的全新漂亮军事装备，最后他们毁了协议，协议说你必须做这个这个这个这个，但他们没做，他们没做，协议被
was terminated by us because they didn't do what they were supposed to do.
被我们终止了，因为他们没有做他们应该做的事。
And these people did the worst withdrawal and, in my opinion, the most embarrassing moment in the history of our country.
这些人进行了最糟糕的撤军，在我看来，这是我们国家历史上最尴尬的时刻。
And by the way, that's why Russia attacked Ukraine, because they saw how incompetent she and her boss are.
顺便说一句，这就是为什么俄罗斯攻击乌克兰，因为他们看到了她和她的老板有多么无能。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢你。
I want to move on now to race and politics in this country.
我想现在谈谈这个国家的种族和政治。
Mr. President, you recently said of Vice President Harris, quote, I didn't know she was black until a number of years ago when she happened to turn black and now she wants to be known as black.
总统先生，你最近说副总统哈里斯，引述，我多年前才知道她是黑人，现在她想被认为是黑人。
I want to ask a bigger picture question here tonight.
今晚我想问一个更大的问题。
Why do you believe it's appropriate to weigh in on the racial identity of your opponent?
你为什么认为评论对手的种族身份是合适的？
I don't and I don't care.
我不评论，我也不在乎。
I don't care what she is.
我不在乎她是什么。
I don't care.
我不在乎。
uh, you make a big deal out of something, I couldn't care less.
呃，你把这事看得太重了，我根本不在乎。
Whatever she wants to be is okay with me.
她想成为什么都可以，我无所谓。
But those were your words.
但那是你的原话。
So I don't know.
所以我不清楚。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I mean, all I can say is I read where she was not black that she put out and I'll say that.
我的意思是，我只知道她不是黑人，她自己说的，我就这么说。
And then I read that she was black and that's okay.
然后我又听说她是黑人，那也没问题。
Either one was okay with me.
对我来说都无所谓。
That's up to her.
这取决于她。
Vice President Harris, your thoughts on this?
副总统哈里斯，您对此有何看法？
I think it's – I mean, honestly, I think it's a tragedy that we have someone who wants to be president who has consistently over the course of his career attempted to use race to divide the American people.
我认为——说实话，我认为这是一个悲剧，我们有一位想当总统的人，他职业生涯中一直试图利用种族来分裂美国人民。
You know, I do believe that the vast majority of us know that we have so much more in common than what separates us, and we don't want this kind of approach that is just constantly trying to divide us, and especially by race.
你知道，我相信我们大多数人都知道，我们共同点远多于分歧，我们不希望这种不断试图分裂我们的做法，尤其是通过种族。
And let's remember how Donald Trump started.
让我们记住唐纳德·特朗普是如何开始的。
He was a land—he owned land, he owned buildings, and he was investigated because he refused to rent.
他是个地产商——他拥有土地，拥有建筑，他因拒绝出租而被调查。
property to black families.
房产给黑人家庭。
Let's remember, this is the same individual who took out a full page ad in the New York Times calling for the execution of five young black and Latino boys who were innocent, the Central Park Five.
让我们记住，这就是同一个人，他在《纽约时报》上刊登整版广告，要求处决五名无辜的黑人和拉丁裔男孩，即中央公园五人。
took out a full-page ad calling for their execution.
刊登整版广告要求处决他们。
This is the same individual who spread birther lies about the first black president of the United States.
这就是同一个人，他散布关于美国首位黑人总统的出生地谎言。
And I think the American people want better than that, want better than this, want someone who understands, as I do, I travel our country.
我认为美国人民想要更好的，想要比这更好的，想要一个像我一样理解的人，我走遍全国。
We see in each other a friend.
我们在彼此身上看到朋友。
We see in each other a neighbor.
我们在彼此身上看到邻居。
We don't want a leader who is constantly trying to have Americans point their fingers at each other.
我们不想要一个不断试图让美国人互相指责的领导人。
I meet with people all the time who tell me
我经常与人见面，他们告诉我
Can we please just have discourse about how we're going to invest in the aspirations and the ambitions and the dreams of the American people?
我们能不能就如何投资于美国人民的抱负、雄心和梦想进行讨论？
Knowing that regardless of people's color or the language their grandmother speaks, we all have the same dreams and aspirations and want a president who invests in those, not in hate and division.
知道无论人们的肤色或祖母说的语言，我们都有相同的梦想和抱负，想要一个投资于这些，而不是仇恨和分裂的总统。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
副总统哈里斯，谢谢您。
Lindsey?
林赛？
President Trump, this is now your third time
特朗普总统，这是您第三次
This is the most divisive presidency in the history of our country.
这是我们国家历史上最具分裂性的总统任期。
There's never been anything like it.
从未有过这样的事情。
They're destroying our country, and they come up with things like what she just said.
他们在摧毁我们的国家，他们提出像她刚才说的那样的事情。
Going back many, many years, when a lot of people, including Mayor Bloomberg, agreed with me on the Central Park Five, they admitted, they said, they pled guilty.
回顾很多年前，包括布隆伯格市长在内，很多人都同意我对中央公园五人的看法，他们承认，他们说，他们认罪了。
And I said, well, if they pled guilty, they'd badly hurt a person, killed a person, ultimately.
我说，好吧，如果他们认罪了，他们严重伤害了一个人，最终杀了一个人。
And if they pled guilty, then they pled.
如果他们认罪，那就认了。
We're not guilty.
我们是无辜的。
But this is a person that has to stretch back years, 40, 50 years ago, because there's nothing now.
但这个人得追溯到几十年前，40年、50年前，因为现在没什么可说的。
I built one of the greatest economies in the history of the world, and I'm going to build it again.
我曾建立了世界上有史以来最伟大的经济体，我还会再建一次。
It's going to be bigger, better and stronger.
它将会更大、更好、更强。
But they're destroying our economy.
但他们正在摧毁我们的经济。
They have no idea what a good economy is.
他们根本不知道什么是好的经济。
Their oil policies, every single policy.
他们的石油政策，每一项政策。
And remember this.
记住这一点。
She is Biden.
她是拜登。
You know, she's trying to get away from Biden.
你知道，她正试图摆脱拜登。
I don't know the gentleman, she says.
我不认识那位先生，她说。
She is Biden.
她是拜登。
The worst inflation we've ever had.
我们有史以来最严重的通货膨胀。
A horrible economy because inflation has made it so bad.
糟糕的经济，因为通货膨胀让它变得如此糟糕。
And she can't get away with that.
她无法摆脱这一点。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Your time is up.
你的时间到了。
I want to respond to that, though.
我想回应一下。
I want to just respond briefly.
我想简短地回应一下。
Clearly, I am not Joe Biden, and I am certainly not Donald Trump.
显然，我不是乔·拜登，当然也不是唐纳德·特朗普。
And what I do offer is a new generation of leadership for our country, one who believes in what is possible, one who brings a sense of optimism about what we can do instead of always disparaging the American people.
我提供的是我们国家新一代的领导力，一个相信可能性的人，一个带来乐观态度的人，而不是总是贬低美国人民。
I believe in what we can do to
我相信我们能做些什么
to strengthen our small businesses, which is why I have a plan.
来加强我们的小企业，这就是为什么我有一个计划。
Let's talk about our plans and let's compare the plans.
让我们谈谈我们的计划，并比较一下这些计划。
I have a plan to give startup businesses $50,000 tax deduction
我有一个计划，为初创企业提供5万美元的税收减免
to pursue their ambitions, their innovation, their ideas, their hard work.
以追求他们的抱负、创新、想法和辛勤工作。
I have a plan, $6,000 for young families for the first year of your child's life to help you in that most critical stage of your child's development.
我有一个计划，为年轻家庭提供6000美元，用于孩子生命的第一年，帮助你在孩子发展的最关键阶段。
I have a plan.
我有一个计划。
That is about allowing people to be able to pursue what has been fleeting in terms of the American dream by offering a help with down payment of $25,000 down payment assistance for first-time home buyers.
这是为了让人们能够追求那些在美国梦中所缺失的东西，通过提供2.5万美元的首付援助，帮助首次购房者。
That's the kind of conversation, I believe, David, that people really want tonight, as opposed to a conversation that is constantly about belittling and name-calling.
我认为，大卫，这才是人们今晚真正想要的对话，而不是那种总是贬低和谩骂的对话。
Let's turn the page and move forward.
让我们翻开新的一页，继续前进。
President Trump, we have to move on.
特朗普总统，我们得继续了。
She has a plan to defund the police.
她有一个计划要削减警察经费。
She has a plan to confiscate everybody's gun.
她有一个计划要没收所有人的枪。
President Trump, we do have to move on to other issues.
特朗普总统，我们确实得继续讨论其他问题了。
in Pennsylvania or anywhere else.
在宾夕法尼亚州或其他任何地方。
That's what her plan is until just recently.
这就是她最近的计划。
The former president has said something twice that I need to respond to.
前总统说了两次我需要回应的话。
I just need to respond one time to what he has said multiple times.
我只需要回应一次他多次说过的话。
President Trump, this is now your third time running for president.
特朗普总统，这是你第三次竞选总统了。
You have long vowed to repeal and replace the Affordable Care Act, also known as Obamacare.
你曾长期誓言要废除并取代《平价医疗法案》，也就是奥巴马医改。
You have failed to accomplish that.
但你未能实现这一目标。
You now say you're going to keep Obamacare, quote, unless we can do something much better.
你现在说你会保留奥巴马医改，除非我们能做得更好。
Last month, you said, quote, we're working on it.
上个月，你说，我们在努力。
So tonight, nine years after you first started running, do you have a plan and can you tell us what it is?
所以今晚，在你第一次竞选九年后，你有一个计划吗？你能告诉我们是什么吗？
Obamacare was lousy health care, always was.
奥巴马医改的医疗保健一直很糟糕。
It's not very good today.
今天也不怎么样。
And what I said, that if we come up with something and we are working on things, we're going to do it and we're going to replace it.
我说过，如果我们能想出更好的方案，我们就会去做，我们会取代它。
But remember this.
但记住这一点。
I inherited Obamacare because Democrats wouldn't change it.
我继承了奥巴马医改，因为民主党人不愿意改变它。
They wouldn't vote for it.
他们不会投票支持。
They were unanimous.
他们是一致的。
They wouldn't vote to change it.
他们不会投票改变它。
If they would have done that, we would have had a much better plan than Obamacare.
如果他们那样做了，我们会有比奥巴马医改好得多的计划。
But the Democrats came up, they wouldn't vote for it.
但民主党人不愿意投票支持。
I had a choice to make when I was president.
我当总统时面临一个选择。
Do I save it and make it as good as it can be, never going to be great, or do I let it rot?
我是保留它并尽可能改善它，尽管它永远不会变得很好，还是让它腐烂？
And I felt I had an obligation, even though politically it would have been good to just let it rot and let it go away.
我觉得我有责任，尽管从政治上讲，让它腐烂并消失会更好。
I decided, and I told my people, the top people, and they're very good people.
我决定，并告诉了我的高层人员，他们是非常优秀的人。
I have a lot of good people in this, that administration.
我有很多优秀的人在这个政府里。
We read about the bad ones.
我们读到了那些不好的。
We had some real bad ones too, and so do they.
我们也有一些真正糟糕的人，他们也一样。
They have really bad ones.
他们确实有一些很糟糕的人。
The difference is they don't get rid of them.
不同的是，他们没有把他们清除掉。
But let me just
但让我
explain.
解释一下。
I had a choice to make.
我面临一个选择。
Do I save it and make it as good as it can be?
我是要拯救它，让它变得尽可能好？
Or do I let it rot?
还是让它腐烂？
And I saved it.
我拯救了它。
I did the right thing.
我做了正确的事。
But it's still never going to be great, and it's too expensive for people.
但它永远不会变得伟大，而且对人们来说太昂贵了。
And what we will do is we're looking at different plans.
我们将要做的是，我们正在考虑不同的计划。
If we can come up with a plan that's going to cost
如果我们能制定出一个计划，这个计划将花费
our people, our population, less money, and be better healthcare than Obamacare, then I would absolutely do it.
我们的人民，我们的人口，更少的钱，并且比奥巴马医改更好的医疗保健，那么我绝对会去做。
But until then, I'd run it as good as it can be run.
但在那之前，我会尽可能好地运行它。
So, just a yes or no, you still do not have a plan?
所以，只是一个是或否，你仍然没有一个计划？
I have concepts of a plan.
我有计划的构想。
I'm not president right now.
我现在不是总统。
But if
但如果
We come up with something.
我们想出了什么。
I would only change it if we come up with something that's better and less expensive.
只有在我们想出了更好且更便宜的东西时，我才会改变它。
And there are concepts and options we have to do that.
我们有一些概念和选项可以做到这一点。
And you'll be hearing about it in the not-too-distant future.
你会在不久的将来听到关于它的消息。
Vice President Harris, in 2017, you supported Bernie Sanders' proposal to do away with private insurance and create a government-run healthcare system.
副总统哈里斯，在2017年，你支持伯尼·桑德斯的提议，取消私人保险，建立一个政府运营的医疗保健系统。
Two years later, you proposed a plan that included a private insurance option.
两年后，你提出了一项包括私人保险选项的计划。
What is your plan today?
你今天的计划是什么？
Well, first of all, I absolutely support, and over the last four years as vice president, private healthcare options, but what we need to do is maintain and grow the Affordable Care Act.
首先，我绝对支持，并且在过去四年作为副总统期间，支持私人医疗保健选项，但我们需要做的是维持并扩大《平价医疗法案》。
But I'll get to that, Lindsay, I just need to respond to a previous point that the former president has made.
但我会谈到那个，林赛，我需要回应前总统之前提出的一个观点。
I've made very clear my position on fracking, and then this business about taking everyone's guns away.
我已经非常明确地表明了我在水力压裂问题上的立场，然后是关于没收所有人枪支的事情。
Tim Walz and I are both gun owners.
蒂姆·沃尔兹和我都是枪支拥有者。
We're not taking anybody's guns away, so stop with the continuous lying about this stuff.
我们不会没收任何人的枪支，所以不要再继续撒谎了。
As it relates to the Affordable Care Act, understand, just look at the history to know where people stand.
关于《平价医疗法案》，了解历史就能知道人们的立场。
When Donald Trump was president, 60 times he tried to get rid of the Affordable Care Act.
当唐纳德·特朗普担任总统时，他试图废除《平价医疗法案》60次。
60 times.
60次。
I was a senator at the time when, I will never forget the early morning hours when it was up for a vote in the United States Senate.
我当时是参议员，我永远不会忘记那天凌晨，法案在美国参议院进行投票的时刻。
And the late, great John McCain, who you have disparaged,
还有已故的伟大人物约翰·麦凯恩，你曾贬低他，
as being, you don't like him, you said, at the time, because he got caught.
你说你不喜欢他，因为他在那时被抓住了把柄。
He was an American hero.
他是一位美国英雄。
The late, great John McCain, I will never forget that night, walked onto the Senate floor and said, no you don't.
已故的伟大人物约翰·麦凯恩，我永远不会忘记那个晚上，他走进参议院说，不，你不能。
No you don't.
不，你不能。
No, you don't get rid of the Affordable Care Act.
不，你不能废除《平价医疗法案》。
You have no plan.
你没有计划。
And what the Affordable Care Act has done is eliminate the ability of insurance companies to deny people with pre-existing conditions.
《平价医疗法案》所做的是消除了保险公司拒绝有预先存在条件的人的能力。
I don't have to tell the people watching tonight, you remember what that was like?
我不需要告诉今晚观看的观众，你们还记得那是什么样子吗？
Remember when an insurance company could deny
记得保险公司可以拒绝
if a child had asthma, if someone was a breast cancer survivor, if a grandparent had diabetes.
如果一个孩子有哮喘，如果有人是乳腺癌幸存者，如果祖父母有糖尿病。
And thankfully, as I've been vice president and we over the last four years have strengthened the Affordable Care Act, we have allowed for the first time Medicare to negotiate drug prices on behalf of you, the American people.
值得庆幸的是，作为副总统，我们在过去四年中加强了《平价医疗法案》，我们首次允许医疗保险为你们，美国人民，协商药品价格。
Donald Trump said he was going to allow Medicare to negotiate
唐纳德·特朗普说他将允许医疗保险协商
drug prices?
药品价格？
He never did.
他从未这样做。
We did.
我们做到了。
And now we have capped the cost of insulin at $35 a month.
现在我们已将胰岛素的价格上限定为每月35美元。
Since I've been vice president, we have capped the cost of prescription medication for seniors at $2,000 a year.
自从我担任副总统以来，我们已经将老年人处方药的费用上限定为每年2000美元。
And when I am president, we will do that for all people, understanding that the value I bring to this
当我成为总统时，我们将为所有人这样做，理解我带来的价值
is that access to health care should be a right and not just a privilege of those who can afford it.
是获得医疗保健应该是每个人的权利，而不仅仅是那些负担得起的人的特权。
And the plan has to be to strengthen the Affordable Care Act, not get rid of it, practice prologue in terms of where Donald Trump stands on that.
计划必须是加强《平价医疗法案》，而不是废除它，从唐纳德·特朗普在这方面的立场来看。
I want to move to an issue that's important for a lot of... You made a mistake.
我想转向一个对很多人来说都很重要的问题……你犯了一个错误。
At number one, John McCain fought Obamacare for 10 years.
首先，约翰·麦凯恩为《平价医疗法案》奋斗了10年。
But it wasn't only him.
但不仅仅是他。
It were all of the Democrats that kept it going.
是所有的民主党人一直在推动它。
And you know what?
你知道吗？
We can do much better than Obamacare, much less money.
我们可以做得比奥巴马医改更好，花更少的钱。
But she won't improve private insurance for people, private medical insurance.
但她不会改善人们的私人保险，私人医疗保险。
That's another thing she doesn't want to get.
这是她不想触及的另一个问题。
People are paying privately for insurance that have worked hard and made money and they want to have private.
人们努力工作赚钱，想要私人保险。
She wants everybody to be on government insurance where you wait.
她希望每个人都加入政府保险，在那里你要等待。
Six months for an operation that you need immediately.
需要立即手术的人要等六个月。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
We have another issue that we'd like to get to that's important for a number of Americans, in particular younger voters, and that's climate change.
我们还有另一个对许多美国人来说重要的问题，特别是年轻选民，那就是气候变化。
President Trump, with regard to the environment, you say that we have to have clean air and clean water.
特朗普总统，关于环境，你说我们必须有清洁的空气和清洁的水。
Vice President Harris, you call climate change an existential threat.
哈里斯副总统，你称气候变化为生存威胁。
The question to you both tonight is what would you do to fight climate change?
今晚的问题是，你们两位将如何应对气候变化？
And Vice President Harris, we'll start with you.
哈里斯副总统，我们先从你开始。
One minute for you each.
每人一分钟。
Well, the former president had said that climate change is a hoax.
前总统曾说气候变化是个骗局。
And what we know is that it is very real.
我们知道这是非常真实的。
You ask anyone who lives in a state who has experienced these extreme weather occurrences, who now is either being denied home insurance or is being jacked up, you ask anybody who has been the victim of what that means in terms of losing their home, having nowhere to go, we know that we can actually deal with this issue.
问问那些经历过极端天气的人，现在要么被拒绝房屋保险，要么保费飙升，问问那些因失去家园、无处可去而受害的人，我们知道我们实际上可以处理这个问题。
The young people of America care deeply about this issue.
美国的年轻人非常关心这个问题。
And I am proud that as vice president over the last four years, we have invested a trillion dollars in a clean energy economy while we have also increased domestic gas production to historic levels.
我很自豪，作为副总统，过去四年我们投资了一万亿美元在清洁能源经济上，同时我们也增加了国内天然气产量到历史新高。
We have created over 800,000 new manufacturing jobs while I have been vice president.
在我担任副总统期间，我们创造了超过80万个新的制造业工作岗位。
We have invested in clean energy to the point that we are opening up factories around the world.
我们投资清洁能源，以至于我们在全球范围内开设工厂。
Donald Trump said he was going to create manufacturing jobs.
唐纳德·特朗普说他要创造制造业工作岗位。
He lost manufacturing jobs.
他失去了制造业工作岗位。
And I'm also proud to have the endorsement of the United Auto Workers and Sean Fain, who also know that part of building a clean energy economy includes investing in American-made products, American automobiles it includes.
我也自豪地获得了美国汽车工人联合会和肖恩·费恩的支持，他们也知道建设清洁能源经济的一部分包括投资美国制造的产品，包括美国汽车。
growing what we can do around American manufacturing and opening up auto plants, not closing them like happened under Donald Trump.
扩大我们在美国制造业的能力，开设汽车工厂，而不是像唐纳德·特朗普时期那样关闭它们。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
哈里斯副总统，谢谢。
That didn't happen under Donald Trump.
那不是在唐纳德·特朗普时期发生的。
Let me just tell you, they lost 10,000 manufacturing jobs this last month.
让我告诉你，上个月他们失去了1万个制造业工作岗位。
It's going, they're all leaving.
他们都在离开。
They're building big auto plants in Mexico, in many cases owned by China.
他们在墨西哥建大型汽车厂，很多时候是由中国拥有的。
They're building these massive plants and they think they're going to sell their cars into the United States because of these people.
他们建造这些巨大的工厂，认为他们会把这些车卖到美国，因为这些人。
What they have given to China is unbelievable, but we're not going to let that.
他们给中国的东西是难以置信的，但我们不会让这种情况继续。
We'll put tariffs on those cars so they can't come into our country because they will kill
我们会对这些车征收关税，这样他们就不能进入我们的国家，因为他们会摧毁
the United Auto Workers and any auto worker, whether it's in Detroit or South Carolina or any other place, what they've done to business and manufacturing in this country is horrible.
美国汽车工人联合会和任何汽车工人，无论是底特律还是南卡罗来纳州，或者其他任何地方，他们对我国商业和制造业的破坏是可怕的。
We have nothing because they refuse.
我们一无所有，因为他们拒绝。
You know, Biden doesn't go after people because supposedly China paid him millions of dollars.
你知道，拜登不追究某些人，据说是中国给了他数百万美元。
He's afraid to do it between him and his son.
他害怕这样做，因为他和他的儿子之间。
They get all this money from Ukraine.
他们从乌克兰得到所有这些钱。
They get all this money from all of these different countries.
他们从所有这些不同的国家得到所有这些钱。
And then you wonder, why is he so loyal to this one, that one, Ukraine, China?
然后你会想，为什么他对这个、那个、乌克兰、中国如此忠诚？
Why is he?
为什么他？
Why did he get $3.5 million from the mayor of Moscow's wife?
为什么他从莫斯科市长的妻子那里得到了350万美元？
Why did he get — why did she pay him $3.5 million?
为什么他得到了——为什么她付给他350万美元？
This is a crooked administration, and they're selling our country down the tubes.
这是一个腐败的政府，他们在把我们的国家卖掉。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
We'll be right back with closing statements from both of our candidates, an historic night, this ABC News presidential debate from Philadelphia.
我们马上回来，两位候选人将发表闭幕词，这是一个历史性的夜晚，这是ABC新闻在费城的总统辩论。
Back in a moment.
稍后回来。
The ABC News presidential debate will continue after this.
ABC新闻的总统辩论将继续进行。
Live from the National Constitution Center in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, here again, David Muir and Lindsay Davis.
从宾夕法尼亚州费城的美国宪法中心现场直播，再次由大卫·缪尔和林赛·戴维斯主持。
Welcome back tonight.
今晚欢迎回来。
The time has come for closing statements.
现在是闭幕词的时间。
And Vice President Harris, we begin with you.
哈里斯副总统，我们从你开始。
So I think you've heard tonight two very different visions for our country, one that is focused on the future and the other that is focused on the past and an attempt to take us backward.
所以我认为今晚你听到了两种截然不同的国家愿景，一种专注于未来，另一种则专注于过去，试图让我们倒退。
But we're not going back.
但我们不会倒退。
And I do believe that the American people know we all have so much more in common than what separates us.
我相信美国人民知道我们共同点远多于分歧。
And we can chart a new way forward.
我们可以开辟一条新的前进道路。
And a vision of that includes having a plan, understanding the aspirations, the dreams, the hopes, the ambition of the American people, which is why I intend to create
这个愿景包括有一个计划，理解美国人民的愿望、梦想、希望和抱负，这就是为什么我打算创造
an opportunity economy, investing in small businesses, in new families, in what we can do around protecting seniors, what we can do that is about giving hardworking folks a break and bringing down the cost of living.
机会经济，投资于小企业、新家庭，以及我们能为保护老年人所做的事情，为辛勤工作的人们减轻负担，降低生活成本。
I believe in what we can do together that is about sustaining America's standing in the world and ensuring that we have the respect that we so rightly deserve, including respecting our military and ensuring we have the most lethal fighting force in the world.
我相信我们能共同做的事情，是关于维持美国在世界上的地位，并确保我们得到应有的尊重，包括尊重我们的军队，确保我们拥有世界上最致命的战斗力量。
I will be a president that will protect our fundamental rights and freedoms, including the right of a woman to make decisions about her own body and not have her government tell her what to do.
我将是一位保护我们基本权利和自由的总统，包括女性对自己身体的决定权，而不是让政府告诉她该做什么。
I'll tell you, I started my career as a prosecutor.
我告诉你，我以检察官的身份开始了我的职业生涯。
I was a DA, I was an Attorney General, a United States Senator, and now Vice President.
我曾是地方检察官、总检察长、美国参议员，现在是副总统。
I've only had one client, the people.
我只有一个客户，那就是人民。
And I'll tell you, as a prosecutor, I never asked a victim or a witness, are you a Republican or a Democrat?
我告诉你，作为一名检察官，我从未问过受害者或证人，你是共和党人还是民主党人？
The only thing I ever asked them, are you okay?
我唯一问过他们的是，你还好吗？
And that's the kind of president we need right now, someone who cares about you and is not putting themselves first.
这就是我们现在需要的总统，一个关心你而不是把自己放在首位的人。
I intend to be a president for all Americans and focus on what we can do over the next 10 and 20 years to build back up our country by investing right now in you, the American people.
我打算成为所有美国人的总统，并专注于我们在未来10到20年里能做的事情，通过现在投资于你，美国人民，来重建我们的国家。
Vice President Harris, thank you.
副总统哈里斯，谢谢你。
President Trump?
特朗普总统？
So she just started by saying she's going to do this, she's going to do that, she's going to do all these wonderful things.
所以她一开始就说她要这样做，她要那样做，她要完成所有这些美好的事情。
Why hasn't she done it?
为什么她还没做？
She's been there for three and a half years.
她已经在那里三年半了。
They've had three and a half years to fix the border.
他们有三年半的时间来修复边境。
They've had three and a half years to
他们有三年半的时间来
create jobs, and all the things we talked about.
创造就业机会，以及我们谈论的所有事情。
Why hasn't she done it?
为什么她还没做？
She should leave right now, go down to that beautiful White House, go to the Capitol, get everyone together and do the things you want to do.
她现在应该离开，去那美丽的白宫，去国会，把所有人都召集起来，做你想做的事情。
But you haven't done it, and you won't do it, because you believe in things that the American people don't believe in.
但你没有做，而且你也不会做，因为你相信的事情是美国人民不相信的。
You believe in things like
你相信的事情比如
We're not going to frack.
我们不会进行水力压裂。
We're not going to take fossil fuel.
我们不会使用化石燃料。
We're not going to do things that are going to make this country strong, whether you like it or not.
我们不会做那些无论你喜欢与否都会让这个国家强大的事情。
Germany tried that.
德国试过那样。
And within one year, they were back to building normal energy plants.
一年之内，他们又回到了建设常规能源厂。
We're not ready for it.
我们还没准备好。
We can't sacrifice our country for the sake of bad vision.
我们不能为了糟糕的愿景而牺牲我们的国家。
But I just ask one simple question.
但我只问一个简单的问题。
Why didn't she do it?
她为什么不做？
We're a failing nation.
我们是一个正在衰败的国家。
We're a nation that's in serious decline.
我们是一个正在严重衰退的国家。
We're being laughed at all over the world.
全世界都在嘲笑我们。
All over the world, they laugh.
I know the leaders very well.
我非常了解这些领导人。
They're coming to see me.
他们来找我。
They call me.
他们给我打电话。
We're laughed at all over the world.
全世界都在嘲笑我们。
They don't understand what happened to us as a nation.
他们不明白我们国家发生了什么。
We're not a leader.
我们不是领导者。
We don't have any idea what's going on.
我们不知道发生了什么。
We have wars going on in the Middle East.
中东正在发生战争。
We have wars going on with Russia and Ukraine.
俄罗斯和乌克兰正在发生战争。
We're going to end up in a third world war and it'll be a war like no other because of nuclear weapons, the power of weaponry.
我们可能会陷入第三次世界大战，这将是一场前所未有的战争，因为核武器，武器的力量。
I rebuilt our entire military.
我重建了我们的整个军队。
She gave a lot of it away to the Taliban.
她把很多都给了塔利班。
She gave it to Afghanistan.
她给了阿富汗。
What these people have done to our country and maybe toughest of all is allowing millions of
这些人对我们国家所做的事情，也许最糟糕的是允许数百万人
people to come into our country.
进入我们的国家。
Many of them are criminals, and they're destroying our country.
他们中的许多人是罪犯，正在摧毁我们的国家。
The worst president, the worst vice president in the history of our country.
有史以来最糟糕的总统，最糟糕的副总统。
President Trump, thank you.
特朗普总统，谢谢。
And that is our ABC News presidential debate from here in Philadelphia at the National Constitution Center.
这是我们在费城国家宪法中心为您带来的ABC新闻总统辩论。
I'm Lindsay Davis.
我是林赛·戴维斯。
And I'm David Muir.
我是大卫·缪尔。
Thank you for watching here in the U.S.
感谢您在美国和世界各地的观看，以及ABC新闻的全体工作人员。
and all over the world and from all of us here at ABC News.
晚安。
Good night.
谢谢观看。
Thanks for watching.
Stay updated about breaking news and top stories on the NBC News app or follow us on social media.
通过NBC新闻应用程序获取最新突发新闻和头条新闻，或在社交媒体上关注我们。